<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Steve Messer // Product manager</title>
    <description>Product person, GOV.UK Pay, Government Digital Service. Web enthusiast, working in the open. Black Country boy living in North Wales, UK.</description>
    <link>https://visitmy.website</link>
    <atom:link href="https://visitmy.website/feed.blogroll.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 18:43:03 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 18:43:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>2020: a year in review</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/-hlQHYtncww&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;lol, fuck that&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://visitmy.website/2020/12/24/2020-year-in-review/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://visitmy.website/2020/12/24/2020-year-in-review/</guid>
        
        <category>Blogroll</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Reading List Picks of 2020</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;First, a confession: there’s a couple of podcasts hidden in this list of articles and blog posts. But putting that one transgression aside, here’s some of the best things I read over the last 12 months that either gave me ideas, crystallised my thinking or started to change my mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a longer list than previous years but there’s plenty in there to fill your browser tabs and bookmarks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#product-management--design&quot;&gt;Product management &amp;amp; design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#digital&quot;&gt;Digital&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-web&quot;&gt;The Web&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#qanon&quot;&gt;QAnon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#futures&quot;&gt;Futures&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#uk-dance-music&quot;&gt;UK dance music&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#just-good-pieces&quot;&gt;Just good pieces&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;product-management--design&quot;&gt;Product management &amp;amp; design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;using-hypotheses-to-hold-together-your-learning-thinking-and-making&quot;&gt;Using hypotheses to hold together your learning, thinking, and making&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first came across how to use hypotheses and lines-in-the-sand on the product management course at General Assembly, and I’ve used the technique successfully in a couple of my product teams over the years. John Waterworth posted this on DXW’s blog earlier this year and I’ve referred back to it a few times since. So I’m sharing it with you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dxw.com/2020/02/using-hypotheses-to-hold-together-your-learning-thinking-and-making/&quot;&gt;Using hypotheses to hold together your learning, thinking, and making&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;calm-product-manager--stressed-product-manager&quot;&gt;Calm Product Manager / Stressed Product Manager&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no doubt that this year has been hard for everyone. There was a moment before the pandemic hit where I was a little stressed out, and I came across this post. It helped me to notice the behaviours I was exhibiting and how those would impact our work, which helped me shift gear and slow down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://productcoalition.com/calm-product-manager-stressed-product-manager-da9957bbb741&quot;&gt;Calm Product Manager / Stressed Product Manager&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;it-takes-two&quot;&gt;It takes two&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A cracking post from Jukesie that illustrates the nuances between product managers and delivery managers on multidisciplinary teams. Though the roles overlap, there’s a clear distinction between each role’s purpose – and when you work together, as a team, excellent things occur. I’ve forwarded it to several people who were worried about stepping on the toes of their colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://digitalbydefault.com/2020/05/06/it-takes-two/&quot;&gt;It takes two&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;product-work-beyond-product-market-fit&quot;&gt;Product Work Beyond Product-Market Fit&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I joined GOV.UK Pay and started reviewing the roadmap with the team leads, usually preceding quarterly planning, I found it hard to have discussions around what to prioritise. Unlike others who’d been on the team longer, I didn’t have a detailed knowledge of recent history and couldn’t easily discuss the work within the product’s strategic context. So I used this article to categorise our work into four groups, helping us decide what to do now, next and later – and what not to do. I find it’s now &lt;em&gt;much easier&lt;/em&gt; to talk about the value of each piece of work relative to all the others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reforge.com/blog/product-work-beyond-product-market-fit&quot;&gt;Product Work Beyond Product-Market Fit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-boring-designer&quot;&gt;The Boring Designer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone shared this with me after reading &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/01/08/boring-magic/&quot;&gt;Boring magic&lt;/a&gt;, and it describes the design approach I think we strive for working on government digital services. It’s not that you can’t add delighters to your product or service, but those delighters are inherently utilitarian. And when it comes to grand visions: ‘If there’s The Big Idea, the boring designer is fantastic at finding a reasonable step one instead of making The Big Idea the starting line.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://capwatkins.com/blog/the-boring-designer&quot;&gt;The Boring Designer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;digital&quot;&gt;Digital&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;russell-daviess-strategy-advice&quot;&gt;Russell Davies’s strategy advice&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last 18 months, I’ve been focused on learning more about strategy. It’s really easy to tie yourself in knots with strategy, it’s such a fluffy concept. But this post by Anna Shipman helped me realise a few things: first, that it pays to be clear, about what you’re not going to do in addition to what you will do; second, that no one person should do it on their own; and third, that if you’re a product manager you’re probably ‘doing strategy’ already, you just hadn’t realised it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.annashipman.co.uk/jfdi/russells-strategy-advice.html&quot;&gt;Russell Davies’s strategy advice&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;delivering-digital-service-this-much-i-have-learned&quot;&gt;Delivering digital service: this much I have learned&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can be tempting to think that, because it moves so fast, working in digital needs new methods, a new focus, or something else to help us deliver better outcomes. So it’s comforting to read this post on what made things work over the last 20 years. If you ever find yourself saying ‘Let’s fix this basics’ in your organisation, I reckon this post is a lightweight owner’s manual for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.mattedgar.com/2020/01/27/delivering-digital-service-this-much-i-have-learned/&quot;&gt;Delivering digital service: this much I have learned&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;multi-hyphenates&quot;&gt;Multi-hyphenates&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You won’t always have access to the specialists you need, and some times you have to fill gaps briefly. That’s where it comes in handy to be a generalist or, as Jukesie calls it, a multi-hyphenate. Not a jack-of-all-trades, but not far off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://digitalbydefault.com/2020/02/12/multi-hyphenates/&quot;&gt;Multi-hyphenates&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dave-rogers-on-trust-and-culture-in-technology-organisations&quot;&gt;Dave Rogers on trust and culture in technology organisations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing I spent all year thinking about was trust and culture in technology organisations. How do you get everyone pushing the same boulder? What makes it feel like a one-in-a-lifetime experience, not a chore? How can we do that in the Internet Age, leaving industrialist methods behind? Dave sums up the qualities of a high-performing, empowered organisation excellently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://daverog.com/2020/07/15/mistrust-makes-technology-toxic/&quot;&gt;Mistrust makes technology toxic&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://daverog.com/2020/08/05/culture-eats-technology-for-breakfast/&quot;&gt;Culture eats technology for breakfast&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-to-debug-distributed-teamwork-as-suggested-by-new-research&quot;&gt;How to debug distributed teamwork, as suggested by new research&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone who previously worked in an office has been thinking about remote, distributed and hybrid working this year. I’ve always been keen on a more flexible working arrangement so spent time researching a range of approaches with my delivery manager, so that we could &lt;a href=&quot;https://gds.blog.gov.uk/2020/10/07/what-happened-when-we-stopped-having-meetings-and-sending-emails/&quot;&gt;experiment with our ways of working on GOV.UK Pay&lt;/a&gt;. This framework from Leisa Reichelt at Atlassian is the step we’ll take next, to consider our colleagues work–life balance from a human-centred perspective, designing our working arrangements around needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.atlassian.com/blog/teamwork/new-research-covid-19-remote-work-impact&quot;&gt;How to debug distributed teamwork, as suggested by new research&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-web&quot;&gt;The Web&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;webwaste&quot;&gt;Webwaste&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of everything I’m sharing this year, this piece had the biggest impact for me personally. Though I knew about the problem of sustainability in digital, Gerry McGovern made it palpable through the everyday examples in this article. It inspired me to &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/07/13/this-website-is-killing-the-planet/&quot;&gt;make this website less carbon-intensive&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://alistapart.com/article/webwaste/&quot;&gt;Webwaste&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;small-b-blogging&quot;&gt;Small b blogging&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post by Tom Critchlow is a lovely piece on the purpose of personal blogs, against a backdrop of content marketing and advertorials. Not quite microblogging and not quite long reads, small-b blogging is all about the serendipity of personal networks. Some times ‘personalisation’ is hand-crafted, not algorithmically ordained.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://tomcritchlow.com/2018/02/23/small-b-blogging/&quot;&gt;Small b blogging&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-does-it-suddenly-feel-like-1999-on-the-internet&quot;&gt;Why does it suddenly feel like 1999 on the internet?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Before social media soured us and made us aloof and dismissive, we used to take the internet’s promise of serendipitous connection more seriously.’ In a similar vein to Tom’s post, this piece in MIT Technology Review points to the resurgence of the Internet’s original phenomenon: feeling part of one giant community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.technologyreview.com/2020/04/03/998480/why-does-it-suddenly-feel-like-1999-on-the-internet/&quot;&gt;Why does it suddenly feel like 1999 on the internet?&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hard-to-believe&quot;&gt;Hard to Believe&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a post about epistemology and how the Web is morphing the definitions of knowledge and information. If you use Google or ask questions to a voice assistant, it’s definitely worth a read. Very relevant for the next section too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thenewatlantis.com/publications/hard-to-believe&quot;&gt;Hard to Believe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;qanon&quot;&gt;QAnon&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having grown up on the Web in the early 2000s, I’m no stranger to conspiracy theories and mis- or disinformation. Every now and then, surfing around corners of the Web, you’d come across something that felt a bit fishy. You developed a sense for which sources to trust and which to ignore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;QAnon represents a mainstream cultural shift, I think, a signifier that normal people are now extremely online, not just nerdy adolescent boys in their bedrooms. It’s obvious when you say it out loud but I hadn’t seen it before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following podcasts and blog posts sum it up evocatively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;First, listen to the Rabbit Hole podcast episodes, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/05/28/podcasts/rabbit-hole-qanon-conspiracy-theory-virus.html&quot;&gt;Where We Go One&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/06/04/podcasts/rabbit-hole-qanon-youtube-tiktok-virus.html&quot;&gt;We Go All&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;then read &lt;a href=&quot;https://mssv.net/2020/08/02/what-args-can-teach-us-about-qanon/&quot;&gt;What ARGs Can Teach Us About QAnon&lt;/a&gt; by Adrian Hon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adrian’s brother Dan also wrote about it in &lt;a href=&quot;https://danhon.substack.com/p/qanon-looks-like-an-alternate-reality&quot;&gt;s08e18: QAnon looks like an alternate reality game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://reallifemag.com/the-apophenic-machine/&quot;&gt;The Apophenic Machine&lt;/a&gt; by Molly Sauter zooms out from ARGs, presenting QAnon in the context of electronic communications, and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;finish on the Reply All podcast, &lt;a href=&quot;https://gimletmedia.com/shows/reply-all/llhe5nm&quot;&gt;Country of Liars&lt;/a&gt;, which pulls back the curtain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;futures&quot;&gt;Futures&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-necessity-of-a-boring-revolution&quot;&gt;The Necessity of a Boring Revolution&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my head, the original vision for Government as a Platform was a strategic design to bring about a boring revolution, setting some of the conditions required for regulatory innovation. Digital government is still on that path, but some of the near-term tactics have changed in the last two years (in the UK at least). Recent moves by the UK, the US and the European Commission to regulate Big Tech shows that regulators may seek to be more nimble and agile in the future too. This piece by the inimitable Indy Johar should helps ignite creative thought in the government digital space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://provocations.darkmatterlabs.org/the-necessity-of-a-boring-revolution-a71b1ae6f956?gi=b4fc88064db5&quot;&gt;The Necessity of a Boring Revolution&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;making-kin-with-the-machines&quot;&gt;Making Kin with the Machines&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘What if we treated AI as equals, like other human beings, not as tools or, worse, slaves to their creators?’ That’s the premise to this paper, which is a wonderful provocation. It’s a really important consideration too, when you consider how many of our decisions we’re asking machine sentience to make for us. If algorithmic bias were a human judge, they’d be thrown out of court (you’d hope).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://jods.mitpress.mit.edu/pub/lewis-arista-pechawis-kite/release/1&quot;&gt;Making Kin with the Machines&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rebooting-progressive-politics-in-the-digital-age&quot;&gt;Rebooting ‘progressive’ politics in the digital age&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Directly related to the two pieces above, this article talks about the inherent relation between software and politics if we’re to make data a key part of policy-making.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://ntouk.wordpress.com/2020/08/14/rebooting-progressive-politics-in-the-digital-age/&quot;&gt;Rebooting ‘progressive’ politics in the digital age&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-coronavirus-is-rewriting-our-imaginations&quot;&gt;The Coronavirus Is Rewriting Our Imaginations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Individualism is giving way to collectivism’ is how I’d summarise this article. In the Great Cyclical Nature of All Things, the neoliberal core of the last 40 years is becoming more apparent to more people, and a politico-social shift is occurring. People are starting to see the routes forward to a new world view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/annals-of-inquiry/the-coronavirus-and-our-future&quot;&gt;The Coronavirus Is Rewriting Our Imaginations&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;it-doesnt-have-to-be-like-this&quot;&gt;It doesn’t have to be like this&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking in much of the above and considering the next step forward in the UK, Jon Alexander considers three shifts that need to occur in how government (small ‘g’) underwrites the social contract for the post-coronavirus future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://jonjalex.medium.com/it-doesnt-have-to-be-like-this-22f0884fbaf&quot;&gt;It doesn’t have to be like this&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;uk-dance-music&quot;&gt;UK dance music&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;an-audience-with-andrew-weatherall&quot;&gt;An Audience with Andrew Weatherall&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The legendary acid house DJ and music producer, who sadly passed away this year, answers questions from the public. Aside from the unequivocal classification of Facebook as unnecessary bullshit, he also touches on how humanity hasn’t changed in 100,000 years, it’s just our technology that has.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uncut.co.uk/features/blogs/an-audience-with-andrew-weatherall-123307/&quot;&gt;An Audience with Andrew Weatherall&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;structural-racism-in-uk-dance-music&quot;&gt;Structural racism in UK dance music&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read these pieces and make up your own mind on what needs to happen next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://djmag.com/longreads/how-much-uk-dance-music-history-real&quot;&gt;How much of UK dance music history is real?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jointhefuture.net/2020/06/04/structural-racism/&quot;&gt;STRUCTURAL RACISM IN UK DANCE MUSIC: TIME FOR ACTION&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thequietus.com/articles/28302-housekeeping-faces-review&quot;&gt;Black Sky Thinking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;just-good-pieces&quot;&gt;Just good pieces&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;working-class-people-dont-need-to-break-into-the-elite--we-need-to-change-it&quot;&gt;Working-class people don’t need to “break into the elite” – we need to change it&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m still processing some of my thoughts and feelings after reading Nathalie Olah’s &lt;em&gt;Steal as much as you can&lt;/em&gt;, but I’m sharing this for anyone else from a working class background. It touches on the themes of her book, which I hope inspire you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.prospectmagazine.co.uk/politics/amol-rajan-break-into-elite-bbc2-documentary-social-mobility-class-uk&quot;&gt;Working-class people don’t need to “break into the elite” – we need to change it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mission-control-a-history-of-the-urban-dashboard&quot;&gt;Mission Control: A History of the Urban Dashboard&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There has been much talk of dashboards this year, the instrumenting of control. This piece covers consoles, cockpits, dashboards and, my favourite, Project Cybersyn, in its short history of evidence-informed analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://placesjournal.org/article/mission-control-a-history-of-the-urban-dashboard/&quot;&gt;Mission Control: A History of the Urban Dashboard&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-battle-of-los-angeles&quot;&gt;The Battle of Los Angeles&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reading this, I realised how much I’d learned about colonialism and structural racism from reading up on Rage lyrics as a teenager. Much more to learn, of course, but &lt;em&gt;Battle&lt;/em&gt; really was a primer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://pitchfork.com/reviews/albums/rage-against-the-machine-the-battle-of-los-angeles/&quot;&gt;The Battle of Los Angeles&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://visitmy.website/2020/12/12/reading-list-picks-of-2020/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://visitmy.website/2020/12/12/reading-list-picks-of-2020/</guid>
        
        <category>Blogroll</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Going dark</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A few pieces I’ve written during NaBloPoMo 2020 have been fun to write. Others were more strained.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure any of them made a good point. I’d like to improve my writing, and committing to writing weeknotes means I can often lose my steam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, good writing starts with good reading, and my note-taking habits have changed recently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By reducing the amount of things I write and publish, I should hopefully give more space for thoughts to percolate, develop and crystallise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’m going dark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;There is a clear overproduction of things (intangible and tangible) that have been created uncritically, unquestioningly, without needing to meet any type of standard other than existing. New output is produced everyday due to the accessibility of tools for creation… We have grown accustomed to shutting off our critical thinking faculties… Critical thinking in action by consumers and creators leads to output being respected and valued accurately, which pushes culture forward towards the infinite cultural mindset.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;https://maekan.com/article/the-modern-creators-paradigm &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://visitmy.website/2020/11/16/going-dark/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://visitmy.website/2020/11/16/going-dark/</guid>
        
        <category>Blogroll</category>
        
        <category>NaBloPoMo</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Many of the things people worry about are not really worth worrying about</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A few years ago I worked with film-maker Tomas Leach on a book for his documentary, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=J7arEQR8PdA&quot;&gt;In No Great Hurry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. The documentary is about the late Saul Leiter, a photographer who made the mundane magnificent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His style is unique. He takes pictures of boring things: condensation on a window, red umbrellas, taxi cars. Moments of urban life we’d all find commonplace. His composition made these scenes hard to unpick, a tad abstract. It would take a few moments to work out what you were seeing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was part of the allure. Shooting in the 1950s and 1960s, he was also an early pioneer of colour photography, which would equally draw the eye after a century of black and white photography.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saul’s photography was boring magic, without a doubt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His style causes us to slow down, to take in more of our surroundings. Inspect the ordinary for shades of delight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often I wonder whether we should be doing that more. In many aspects of life. We needn’t always be in motion, always moving on to the next thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if now is just enough?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’m a person who likes to postpone things. I see no reason for being in a rush. When you consider many of the things that people treat very seriously, you realise that they don’t deserve to be treated that seriously. And many of the things people worry about are not really worth worrying about. If I didn’t do anything more than my little book, would that have been enough? – Saul Leiter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Nothing came of the project, unfortunately. I experienced a severe bout of depression and couldn’t carry on. I really wish I had. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://visitmy.website/2020/11/05/many-things-people-worry-about-are-not-worth-worrying-about/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://visitmy.website/2020/11/05/many-things-people-worry-about-are-not-worth-worrying-about/</guid>
        
        <category>Blogroll</category>
        
        <category>NaBloPoMo</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Silly ideas</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the years I’ve kept these silly ideas for apps and gadgets in a note on my phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of them are really silly, bordering on pointless. For a while that was a particular focus, pointlessness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;An app for recording how quickly your toenails grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;An app that utilises AI to compute when your urine will start smelling of asparagus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;IoT-controlled wind chime, allowing you to turn it off when it’s annoying. It comes with a mini fan for when there’s no wind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there’s one I really want to build: Deliveroulette.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter your post code, a time to be fed and your budget, anything from £20 to £50. A bot will randomly select a restaurant, pick some things off the menu and place the order for you. A little while later the doorbell rings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A surprise dinner!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s better than TimeHop for toenails, anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://visitmy.website/2020/11/04/silly-ideas/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://visitmy.website/2020/11/04/silly-ideas/</guid>
        
        <category>Blogroll</category>
        
        <category>NaBloPoMo</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Google Search is the fast-food restaurant of knowledge</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Getting hold of knowledge is harder than we think. Most of what a search engine returns is information, and it’s our job to piece it together and generate knowledge: facts and things we know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google is really, really good at giving you information and lots of it. But, on average, how many of us click more than one link from the first five results? How many of us honestly take snippets from multiple sources and reason our own judgements?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In making it easy to get to information, Google has made itself a primary source of knowledge nutrition. But it is, at best, a fast-food restaurant: highly operationalised basic sustenance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it’s bad to rely on these behemoths. Most people don’t eat only at McDonald’s. So why feed our brains, our arguments, our faculties of reasoning, on a similar giant?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was product manager for GOV.UK’s site search engine, I set the team a project to learn more about how search engines work. For one week, they had to change their main search provider from Google to something else. Bing, Baidu, Dogpile, DuckDuckGo, Ecosia, or anything else. At the end of the week we talked about what was harder or took more effort, the features they missed from Google, and whether they wanted to carry on using that provider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people said yes, some people switched back to Google, but all of us learned how to find things in a different way. We had to actively engage our epistemological faculties and work with a corpus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then I’ve been using DuckDuckGo every day because I like the way it works. It reminds me of the early web, around 2002, a time when AltaVista and AskJeeves were big names in web search. Back then you’d fall into rabbit holes, starting on one page and diving through links, resurfacing to open up another, related rabbit hole by searching again. We built up information this way. You’d be delighted at what you found sometimes, learning something you hadn’t expected to find.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That pursuit of digging into a topic and building up your own knowledge base is losing ground to instant gratification. Voice assistants, in taking away the hassle of having to &lt;em&gt;read&lt;/em&gt;, could take it away all together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How might we make our own information-gathering Michelin starred? What skills do we need to refresh or relearn?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These habits of mind – how we weigh up information and find truth –  are helpful in many places. Not only in our work projects but also, most critically, at the ballot box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“We do not and cannot gain knowledge by passively recording reality in declarative sentences, as if we were baskets ready to be filled; instead, we must handle it interactively.” – Luciano Floridi&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Some things that inspired this post: Matt Webb’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://interconnected.org/home/2020/09/10/streak&quot;&gt;15 rules for blogging&lt;/a&gt;; Motherboard’s piece on popular culture as an information conduit and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en/article/y3gg3k/tiktok-influencer-isodope-is-stanning-for-nuclear-energy&quot;&gt;nuclear energy influencer Isodope&lt;/a&gt;; and The New Atlantis on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thenewatlantis.com/publications/hard-to-believe&quot;&gt;whether search engines make us gullible&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://visitmy.website/2020/11/03/google-fast-food-knowledge/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://visitmy.website/2020/11/03/google-fast-food-knowledge/</guid>
        
        <category>Blogroll</category>
        
        <category>NaBloPoMo</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why I write weeknotes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Each weekend I spend around 2 hours writing about what I did in the ~38 hours I spent at work that week. Why? Good question. Here’s a few reasons why spending more time than is necessary writing about work is a good thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;it-helps-me-think&quot;&gt;It helps me think&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing is a reflective practice. By going over what you did and writing about it, considering the objectives you were trying to meet and whether you got there, you actively think through and reflect on your work. You spot areas for improvement or things you forgot to do. Whereas otherwise you might canter through working life unsure of what worked or what didn’t, weeknoting makes you mindful of what you’re doing and why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;it-makes-professional-development-easier&quot;&gt;It makes professional development easier&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each month I chat with my line manager about what I’ve been doing at work and how I’m progressing against my professional objectives. Because those conversations are based around what I’ve been doing – and we do &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; – having it written down is super helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;it-builds-networks&quot;&gt;It builds networks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some times I’ve written about a problem we’ve been having, and other people have got in touch to say they have that problem too. Then we chat about it and think of a way forward, or they tell me how they’ve solved it before. This kind of networking, which happens outside your immediate work bubble, is spontaneous but just as useful as established, near networks at work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;it-builds-social-mobility&quot;&gt;It builds social mobility&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I come from a working class background and was the first person in my family to go to university. That means I didn’t learn about office culture, its politics and how to get ahead as a white-collar worker until I started working in an office. My dad is a builder, not a CEO or politician, so tales at the dinner table didn’t prepare me for where I work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I’ve found that by reading through other people’s weeknotes I can get a sense for how things are done. By writing my own notes and putting them out in the open, I have to actively walk the walk as much as talk the talk. By building credibility and showing my working in a sector renowned for cronyism, I’m hopefully proving my worth to prospective employers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;its-a-tiny-tiny-public-service&quot;&gt;It’s a tiny, tiny public service&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a way, the taxpayer is funding everything I do at work, so they probably have a right to know what I’m doing. And one day someone might fill my place and want to know what I got up to. Weeknotes are searchable records of (almost) everything I did at work, providing a history for those who come after me. &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/01/25/blogging-working-open/&quot;&gt;Blogging and working in the open&lt;/a&gt; as a public servant helps to open up government, form a dialogue with our audience, and share what we’ve learnt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the scale of public services they’re not &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; important, obviously. They’re not universal healthcare. But if one other person saves time solving a problem using my notes, that’s a good thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;further-reading&quot;&gt;Further reading&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://boingboing.net/2018/07/25/deep-nerd-ruminations.html&quot;&gt;Weeknotes: personal, public logs in the tradition of early blogging&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/job-garden/a-pre-history-of-weeknotes-plus-why-i-write-them-and-perhaps-why-you-should-too-week-16-31a4a5cbf7b0&quot;&gt;A pre-history of weeknotes, plus why I write them and perhaps why you should too&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://productforthepeople.xyz/the-why-of-weeknotes-c1cd98967842&quot;&gt;The why of weeknotes&lt;/a&gt; by Jukesie&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stamanfar.medium.com/the-why-of-weeknotes-cf4d7e8ad4e5&quot;&gt;The why of weeknotes&lt;/a&gt; by Sam Villis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gilest.org/2020/tips-for-writing-good-weeknotes/&quot;&gt;Tips for writing good weeknotes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://visitmy.website/2020/11/01/why-i-write-weeknotes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://visitmy.website/2020/11/01/why-i-write-weeknotes/</guid>
        
        <category>Blogroll</category>
        
        <category>NaBloPoMo</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>NaBloPoMo 2020</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;An index of things I have written during November 2020 for National Blog Posting Month. You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://visitmy.website/feed.nablopomo.xml&quot;&gt;follow my NaBloPoMo RSS feed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/11/01/why-i-write-weeknotes/&quot;&gt;Why I write weeknotes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/11/02/free-range-future-of-work/&quot;&gt;The free-range future of work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/11/03/google-fast-food-knowledge/&quot;&gt;Google Search is the fast-food restaurant of knowledge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/11/04/silly-ideas/&quot;&gt;Silly ideas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/11/05/many-things-people-worry-about-are-not-worth-worrying-about/&quot;&gt;Many of the things people worry about are not really worth worrying about&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/11/06/users-trust-delivery/&quot;&gt;Users, Trust, Delivery: leading teams with memes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/11/07/rhetoric/&quot;&gt;Rhetoric: leading teams with memes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/11/08/propaganda/&quot;&gt;Propaganda: leading teams with memes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/11/16/going-dark/&quot;&gt;Going dark&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://visitmy.website/2020/11/01/nablopomo-2020/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://visitmy.website/2020/11/01/nablopomo-2020/</guid>
        
        <category>Blogroll</category>
        
        <category>NaBloPoMo</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>This website is killing the planet</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For a while I’ve been intending to make my website more sustainable, but I succumbed, as I often do, to the human trait of sloth. But this morning after reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://alistapart.com/article/webwaste/&quot;&gt;Gerry McGovern’s post on webwaste&lt;/a&gt;, I thought I’d procrastinated long enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I ran a web page performance test and got some &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.webpagetest.org/result/200713_XX_e2daed33a24cd8a099d930fc373b1083/&quot;&gt;grim results&lt;/a&gt;: my website takes over a minute to load on a Moto G4 on using 3G data networks. It’s just as bad &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.webpagetest.org/result/200713_6E_4e249b485a45882604420068caa21ae0/&quot;&gt;using a desktop PC in Nottingham on 1.5Mbps DSL&lt;/a&gt;. My website is bloated with large images and a bunch of JavaScript, which means it’s eating up lots of energy transmitting those bits and bytes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But how much energy? I used the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.websitecarbon.com&quot;&gt;Website Carbon Calculator&lt;/a&gt; to find out. It turns out that&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6.90g of CO2 is produced every time someone visits the homepage&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;it emits the amount of carbon that 4 trees absorb in a year, and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;it uses enough electricity to drive an electric car 1,116km&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eugh. That’s disgusting. For each year my website has been online, I should have planted 4 trees just for the homepage alone. But, instead, my laziness has filled the atmosphere with more and more carbon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to do something, this has gone on long enough, so I’m committing to some actions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’ll move my site to a web hosting provider using renewable energy, one that’s listed on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thegreenwebfoundation.org/directory/&quot;&gt;Green Web Foundation’s directory&lt;/a&gt;. ✅&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’ll compress and optimise the images on my site using &lt;a href=&quot;https://imageoptim.com/mac&quot;&gt;ImageOptim&lt;/a&gt;. ✅&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’ll get rid of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/samesies/barber-jekyll&quot;&gt;my energy-guzzling site theme&lt;/a&gt; until I can introduce one that’s lightweight and accessible. ✅&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Going forward, my website will enshrine the principles of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sustainablewebmanifesto.com&quot;&gt;Sustainable Web Manifesto&lt;/a&gt;. 📝&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’ll pay for some trees to be planted that’ll reduce the impact of my website’s carbon footprint going forward. ✅ &lt;a href=&quot;https://treesforlife.org.uk/groves/249395/&quot;&gt;View the certificate 📜&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To show my commitment to being a good web citizen, I’ll add the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.websitecarbon.com/badge/&quot;&gt;Website Carbon Badge&lt;/a&gt; to all pages ✅ and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thegreenwebfoundation.org/green-web-check/&quot;&gt;Green Web Foundation’s renewable hosting badge&lt;/a&gt; ✅. Once I’ve improved things, I’ll add a &lt;a href=&quot;https://carbontxt.org/&quot;&gt;carbon.txt&lt;/a&gt; ✅.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day I’ll actually get around to building a solar-powered battery bank and run my site off my home connection, but until then I’m taking small steps to remove, minimise and clean-up my presence on the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s the carbon footprint of your website? What steps will you take to reduce it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;further-reading&quot;&gt;Further reading&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://alistapart.com/article/webwaste/&quot;&gt;Webwaste&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pxlnv.com/blog/bullshit-web/&quot;&gt;The bullshit web&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wholegraindigital.com/blog/sustainable-web-design/&quot;&gt;3 steps to creating zero carbon websites&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2018/09/how-to-build-a-lowtech-website.html&quot;&gt;How to build a low-tech website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thegreenwebfoundation.org/news/notes-for-greening-internet-governance-at-eurodig/&quot;&gt;Greening Internet governance: environmental sustainability and digital transformation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been great to read everyone’s responses to this post, even those &lt;a href=&quot;https://buttondown.email/hillelwayne/archive/no-your-clean-code-wont-save-the-planet/&quot;&gt;questioning the merit of reducing carbon emissions on a personal website&lt;/a&gt;. Here’s action others have decided to take on their own websites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://kevq.uk/how-local-fonts-can-save-the-environment/&quot;&gt;Trying To Go Green With Local Fonts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://so.nwalsh.com/2020/10/31-dust&quot;&gt;Please pardon the dust&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tomgamon.com/posts/is-it-morally-wrong-to-write-inefficient-code/&quot;&gt;Is it morally wrong to write inefficient code?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://visitmy.website/2020/07/13/this-website-is-killing-the-planet/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://visitmy.website/2020/07/13/this-website-is-killing-the-planet/</guid>
        
        <category>Blogroll</category>
        
        <category>Popular</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blogging and working in the open</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a talk I gave to the GDS product management community a year ago. It’s mostly aimed at other people working in digital transformation of government, but actually I think everyone should blog a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s lots of ways of working in the open, blogging is just one of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-what-is-the-point-of-blogging&quot;&gt;So what is the point of blogging?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First we should define what a blog is. The noun ‘blog’ means a regularly updated website or web page, typically one run by an individual or small group, that is written in an informal or conversational style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blogs have been a part of the Web since the 1990s when web publishing tools were made easier-to-use for non-technical folk. They’ve always tended to be in a diary style, allowing people to talk about what they do, their interests and anything they please.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;but-whats-the-point-of-blogging-in-government&quot;&gt;But what’s the point of blogging in government?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blogging helps to&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;open up government&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;form a dialogue with our audience&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;share what we’ve learnt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s really all about starting conversations and sharing knowledge. The audience might be fellow service creators or it might be end users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it’s worthwhile taking this a step further. Blogging is all about working in the open. Working in the open causes you to be honest about your work and makes it easier to collaborate with smart communities of peers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll expand on that…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-the-point-of-being-open&quot;&gt;What’s the point of being open?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/government-transformation-strategy-2017-to-2020/government-transformation-strategy-tools-processes-and-governance&quot;&gt;Government Transformation Strategy&lt;/a&gt; says that ‘a culture of open, digitally enabled policy making and service delivery is critical to our future success.’ It’s written into our values as an organisation too: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/guidance/government-design-principles#make-things-open-it-makes-things-better&quot;&gt;‘Make things open, it makes things better.’&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being open is about the importance of working across organisational boundaries to make things better for users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If someone in Department A talks about a particular problem and someone in Department B says they’ve encountered the same thing, they’re likely to ignore the boundaries and differences between their departments and explore the problem together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The shared goal is making things better for users and working in the open helps facilitate that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, more formally, what are the goals of openness?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And these don’t just cover blogging, they can be attributed to our day-to-day practice too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-goals-of-openness&quot;&gt;The goals of openness&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These come from &lt;a href=&quot;https://openmatt.org/2011/04/06/how-to-work-open/&quot;&gt;Open Matt&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog-participation.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Participation&lt;/strong&gt;: it’s rocket-fuel for smart collaboration. Speaking outside of your organisational box can attract other people, get conversations started and accelerate collaboration. (Joined-up working, yeah?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog-agility.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agility&lt;/strong&gt;: speed, flexibility, getting shit done. When you work in the open, you’re more likely to check what you’re saying before putting it out there. It encourages a better, more accountable working practice, as well as working out how to build the right thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog-momentum.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Momentum&lt;/strong&gt;: communities want to push boulders that are already moving. Simply put, working in the open is cheap PR. People love to get involved in exciting projects headed in the right direction. One of my favourite stories is how Neil Williams got offered a job at GDS because he blogged so enthusiastically about a single government website, and Tom Loosemore happened to spot it. But you see this with the Local Digital Coalition too. Teams in previously under-the-radar councils becoming visibly active in improving their authority’s ways of working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog-testing.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Testing and rapid prototyping&lt;/strong&gt;: refining as we go. Working in the open creates better feedback and testing loops, and the history of changes is documented. You have the opportunity to welcome a more diverse set of voices to comment on your work, which is always a good thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog-leverage.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leverage&lt;/strong&gt;: getting greater bang from our limited resources. And again, blogging is really cheap PR. I’ve personally made a ton of good connections I didn’t expect simply by talking about what I’ve done. Don’t worry about making things too polished though, raw honesty (or slightly processed honesty – runny honey) is some of the secret sauce to making it work. (That means you can talk about failure as well as success.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-why-blog-about-our-work&quot;&gt;So why blog about our work?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blogging is not about thought leadership or public performance, it’s about actively feeding the conversation around agile, user-centred transformation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By putting our experiences out there and talking about the new challenges we’re facing, people can empathise or respond, developing the transformation project we’re all a part of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we should be more open to talking about failure too, or announcing when things didn’t go to plan. Not to call ourselves out but help others later down the line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an excellent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dxw.com/2019/02/discovery-embracing-the-unknowns/&quot;&gt;quote&lt;/a&gt; from Ellie Craven who used to be the PM on GOV.UK Registers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;‘The more we obscure how we work, and why it’s valuable, the harder we’ll find it to gain broad organisational support for the next project, and the one after that.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talking about our work helps us better describe it and its value across government. It also gives you a chance to show your working without that person needing to attend a talk or Show &amp;amp; Tell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then she goes one better…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;‘We should do the hard work to &lt;strong&gt;make this simpler for those who come after us&lt;/strong&gt;.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s my emphasis, but talking about our work &lt;em&gt;now&lt;/em&gt; helps people who might one day step into our shoes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So going back to what I said before, blogging helps to&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;open up government&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;form a dialogue with our audience&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;share what we’ve learnt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;some-principles&quot;&gt;Some principles&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some principles (for civil servants) then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/civil-service-code/the-civil-service-code&quot;&gt;Civil Service Code&lt;/a&gt; underpins everything. Stick by that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the first real rule, &lt;strong&gt;don’t be a dick&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try not to be the person to say the wrong thing or inadvertently give away a ministerial plan or cause offence to a team member. None of that is good, but you can mitigate it by asking a second pair of eyes to look over your work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ask someone before mentioning them&lt;/strong&gt;, they might be staying away from the ‘spotlight’. One of my colleagues doesn’t use social media, for example, and wants to stay away from it, so I only ever referred to them as ‘our delivery manager’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spoilers suck&lt;/strong&gt;, so avoid telling another team’s story. They might be doing great things but try not to build too much of a picture if you must mention it. They should have the right to cause a splash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-can-i-start-blogging&quot;&gt;How can I start blogging?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully that’s done enough to convince you to get started. So here’s a few tips to get going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog-kanban.png&quot; alt=&quot;A 'Blog' column on a kanban board&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add a ‘Blog’ column to your kanban board. It’ll help you consider which pieces of work are worth sharing and talking about. You might even build up a few stories per sprint to talk about. Break it down into smaller chunks, it’s much easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to start small and maybe try something more personal, &lt;a href=&quot;https://productforthepeople.xyz/the-why-of-weeknotes-c1cd98967842&quot;&gt;weeknotes&lt;/a&gt; are a great way to get going. Weeknotes are personal reflections on your working week to learn from what you’ve done and improve your practice from week to week. You simply write about what you’ve done and how you feel about how it went.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s an excellent community on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/search?q=%23weeknotes&quot;&gt;#weeknotes&lt;/a&gt; hashtag on Twitter who can give you ideas, but you can also just ask for help. They’re super friendly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s worth saying that blogging isn’t an easy thing to start, you’ll probably get ‘the fear’ about receiving criticism on your work or thoughts. But that’s fine, my advice is to just dive in and have a go. Usually your fears don’t match reality, and there’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://weeknot.es&quot;&gt;an amazing community&lt;/a&gt; there to comment and help if you’re struggling anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you’re worried about writing about work in the public domain, don’t. It’s OK. You have permission. People high up at director level are doing it, just take a look at what &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.mattedgar.com/category/weeknotes/&quot;&gt;Matt Edgar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://roxane-m-heaton.medium.com/weeknotes-s01e01-4e7f2ffe760f&quot;&gt;Rox Heaton&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://rossferg.medium.com/week-1-on-gov-uk-6b40e14d5c1e&quot;&gt;Ross Ferguson&lt;/a&gt; are doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t need any money to get started, really, you can spin up a blog in minutes using platforms like &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.com&quot;&gt;Wordpress&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a quick way to test out the practice and see if it’s right for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to create your own website, static site generators like &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://gohugo.io&quot;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; are low-tech ways to get started. You might have heard of &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com&quot;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt; which runs on Jekyll. You simply feed it some Markdown files and it builds a website for you. GitHub Pages is free too, and it’s a good way to become more familiar with Git in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And you needn’t worry about having to promote your blog posts either. Services like &lt;a href=&quot;https://lttr.ai/Mg8L&quot;&gt;Missinglettr&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://zapier.com&quot;&gt;Zapier&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://quuu.co/promote&quot;&gt;Quuu Promote&lt;/a&gt; will syndicate your blog posts on social media automatically, helping your posts to get a greater reach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/self-facilitating-media-node.gif&quot; alt=&quot;A scene from Nathan Barley&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may become a self-facilitating media node. That’s fine. The goal is to share knowledge and passion and get more people involved in agile, user-centred transformation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-note-on-passion&quot;&gt;A note on passion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the talk, I asked members of the audience to raise their hand if they wanted to work at GDS after reading one of its blog posts. 75 per cent of people put their hand up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thank you to &lt;a href=&quot;https://digitalbydefault.com&quot;&gt;Matt Jukes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ayymanduh&quot;&gt;Amanda Smith&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://gilest.org&quot;&gt;Giles Turnbull&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/neillyneil&quot;&gt;Neil Williams&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://danbarrett.posthaven.com&quot;&gt;Dan Barrett&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@Ellayanor&quot;&gt;Ellie Craven&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@stamanfar&quot;&gt;Sam Villis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.caffeinatedpunctuation.co.uk&quot;&gt;Jonathan Kerr&lt;/a&gt; and the #weeknotes folks, stalwarts of the blogging and working in the open community who inspired this.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;further-reading&quot;&gt;Further reading&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gilest.org/agile-comms-tips.html&quot;&gt;Agile communication tips&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gds.blog.gov.uk/2019/08/27/podcast-on-writing/&quot;&gt;On writing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://productforthepeople.xyz/the-importance-of-being-open-92f81eaee7f9&quot;&gt;The importance of being open&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/11/01/why-i-write-weeknotes/&quot;&gt;Why I write weeknotes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amyhupe.co.uk/articles/lets-write-more-blog-posts-an-experiment/&quot;&gt;Let’s write more blog posts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tomcritchlow.com/2018/02/23/small-b-blogging/&quot;&gt;Small b blogging&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20061128082434/http://dig.csail.mit.edu/breadcrumbs/node/170&quot;&gt;Blogging is great&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gilest.org/2020/tips-for-writing-good-weeknotes/&quot;&gt;Tips for writing good weeknotes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://visitmy.website/2020/01/25/blogging-working-open/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://visitmy.website/2020/01/25/blogging-working-open/</guid>
        
        <category>Blogroll</category>
        
        <category>Digital government</category>
        
        <category>Popular</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Reading List Picks of 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s a bunch of articles and blog posts that got me thinking about digital government, product management, design thinking, the World Wide Web and data this year. There’s also a couple of nice stories I enjoyed thrown in. Oh, and some stuff about attention too, because this list is full of useful distractions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve not included anything about privacy, which I should have, but I think that probably deserves its own post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;digital-government&quot;&gt;Digital government&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;just-enough-internet-why-public-service-internet-should-be-a-model-of-restraint&quot;&gt;Just enough Internet: Why public service Internet should be a model of restraint&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heavyweight thinking on good, responsible technology in public service from Rachel Coldicutt, which has been this year’s hot topic alongside privacy. Rachel’s piece does well to bring together thinking from across the public service space, including sessions from MozFest 2018, viewing it through a lens of sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.doteveryone.org.uk/2019/10/just-enough-internet/&quot;&gt;Just enough Internet: Why public service Internet should be a model of restraint&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;there-is-no-such-thing-as-the-government&quot;&gt;There is no such thing as the government&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was posted in 2010, around the time &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/directgov-2010-and-beyond-revolution-not-evolution-a-report-by-martha-lane-fox&quot;&gt;Martha Lane Fox’s report on Directgov&lt;/a&gt; was published, leading to the creation of Government Digital Service and GOV.UK. In it Stefan Czerniawski talks about how the dream for joined-up government services has been around for years, and it’s a key historical text for anyone working in the current era of transformation&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. (There’s bonus archived blog posts from &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tomskitomski&quot;&gt;Tom&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/neillyneil&quot;&gt;Neil&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jukesie&quot;&gt;Jukesie&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.publicstrategist.com/2010/11/there-is-no-such-thing-as-the-government/&quot;&gt;There is no such thing as the government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-problem-with-the-service-lifecycle&quot;&gt;The problem with the service lifecycle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The service design lifecycle in government has four stages: discovery, alpha, beta, live. It’s an agile technique from the world of software development, and its aim is to help teams and organisations create new things while reducing waste. But it’s a linear strategy with a resolute end, it doesn’t set you up for what’s next. Sanjay put forward the idea of the lifecycle as a spiral, which I really like as it helps you think about step-changes. You might have digitised a bunch of paper forms, but how might you discover the bigger problem to solve?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@sanjaypoyzer/the-problem-with-the-service-lifecycle-5efe278f5119&quot;&gt;The problem with the service lifecycle&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;data-sharing-in-government-why-its-time-for-a-new-approach&quot;&gt;Data-sharing in government: why it’s time for a new approach&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If bits of government start using more data to design and deliver things, what will people think about government and will they trust it? This is one of many pieces Richard has written in his &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastcompany.com/3066631/software-is-politics&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;software is politics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; genre, but it’s a good one for considering how the social contract plays into trust models and data re-use. Essentially: there should be clear lines of accountability and responsibility for citizens to have recourse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/digitalhks/data-sharing-in-government-why-democracies-must-change-direction-badfaa2463ec&quot;&gt;Data-sharing in government: why it’s time for a new approach&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;product-management--design-thinking&quot;&gt;Product management &amp;amp; design thinking&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;right-question-wrong-answer-agile-stakeholder-management&quot;&gt;Right question, wrong answer: agile stakeholder management&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most product teams will know about HiPPOs – the highest paid person in the organisation – and their opinions. Sometimes senior people will ask why a team hasn’t produced a particular output, and Matt puts forward a helpful mindset for breaking that down. It’s easy to get dismayed or irked in those situations but this piece sets a principled approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iterate.org.uk/right-question-wrong-answer-agile-stakeholder-management/&quot;&gt;Right question, wrong answer: agile stakeholder management&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;resources-for-applying-a-systems-lens-to-your-work&quot;&gt;Resources for applying a systems lens to your work&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent a lot of time looking at the bigger picture in work this year and came across this post in the summer. It has a a bunch of great resources for how to address root causes, not symptoms of problems – systems-thinking. Even reading the first book on the list, Dan Hill’s &lt;em&gt;Dark Matter and Trojan Horses&lt;/em&gt;, changed the way I work. Make your way through the list, it’s great. Shout-out to Aly (and Will, of course).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@alyblenkin/resources-for-applying-a-systems-lens-to-your-work-8ebee73227bd&quot;&gt;Resources for applying a systems lens to your work&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-new-social-contract&quot;&gt;A New Social Contract&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first post in a four-part series on redesigning democracy from Alastair Parvin. He’s done incredibly well to set the problems and proposed solutions within their context, making it all relatable. An expert use of storytelling and systems-thinking to propose new futures, with a nod to &lt;a href=&quot;https://public.digital/2018/09/25/making-government-as-a-platform-real/&quot;&gt;government as a platform&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@AlastairParvin/a-new-social-contract-359c426e0f61&quot;&gt;A New Social Contract&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-you-should-stop-using-product-roadmaps-and-try-gist-planning&quot;&gt;Why you should stop using product roadmaps and try GIST planning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A decent framework from Itamar Gilad that wraps in Lean Startup methods, OKRs, and a pipeline for testing ideas, all sat beneath the organisation’s shared goals and strategy. I tried it out on the Search team and we made some good progress. A good way to avoid the agile build trap, do more prototyping, and empower product teams to deliver outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@itamargilad/why-i-stopped-using-product-roadmaps-and-switched-to-gist-planning-3b7f54e271d1&quot;&gt;Why you should stop using product roadmaps and try GIST planning&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-read-about-design-for-trust-so-you-dont-have-to&quot;&gt;I Read About “Design For Trust” So You Don’t Have To&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does what it says on the tin. A compendium of links to and a summary of many ‘design for trust’ posts from across the Web. (It’s worth reading all the content the author draws on though!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://simplysecure.org/blog/design-trust&quot;&gt;I Read About “Design For Trust” So You Don’t Have To&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-world-is-distracted&quot;&gt;The world is distracted&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-machine-stops&quot;&gt;The Machine Stops&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Either peak smartphone isn’t far off or we’ve reached it already. The late neurologist Oliver Sacks writes about the disappearence of old civilities, where people have replaced talking to their neighbours with talking to their phones. But there’s hope in this piece too, that people will realise the need to sustain the richness of human cultures. And since more of us are putting our phones down, I’m hopeful too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2019/02/11/the-machine-stops&quot;&gt;The Machine Stops&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-attention-economy&quot;&gt;The attention economy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Owen Williams puts forward the idea that most products are competing for the space in front of your eyeballs. Attention is now a commodity as much as technology, and the only limit is the population and the number of waking hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://char.gd/recharged/daily/the-attention-economy&quot;&gt;The attention economy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-case-for-doing-nothing&quot;&gt;The Case for Doing Nothing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Niksen&lt;/em&gt; is the Dutch concept of embracing boredom to stop ourselves being so busy. It’s a bit like mindfulness, only you don’t need to pay Headspace a subscription fee to learn how to do it. This piece makes the case for doing nothing with purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/04/29/smarter-living/the-case-for-doing-nothing.html&quot;&gt;The Case for Doing Nothing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-web-and-data&quot;&gt;The Web and data&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;30-years-on-whats-next-fortheweb&quot;&gt;30 years on, what’s next #ForTheWeb?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The World Wide Web is 30 years old, so I couldn’t not include this. Since you’re using the Web, please read it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://webfoundation.org/2019/03/web-birthday-30/&quot;&gt;30 years on, what’s next #ForTheWeb?&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-internets-back-to-the-land-movement&quot;&gt;The Internet’s Back-to-the-Land Movement&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following on from the piece by &lt;em&gt;Lowtech&lt;/em&gt; magazine in &lt;a href=&quot;/2018/12/23/reading-list-picks-of-2018/&quot;&gt;last year’s picks&lt;/a&gt;, this piece by Becca Abbe talks about moving off-grid in a digital sense: opting out of mainstream internet providers and building independent mesh networks or a peer-to-peer Web. Whatever the solution, making things more sustainable is a critical consideration for the next few decades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.are.na/blog/the-internet's-back-to-the-land-movement&quot;&gt;The Internet’s Back-to-the-Land Movement&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-rise-and-demise-of-rss&quot;&gt;The Rise and Demise of RSS&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RSS is one of those wonderful Web technologies, meaning you can follow updates from anyone across the world. In simple terms, it’s a bit like tweets without Twitter. But depsite getting off to a good start, RSS has all but disappeared as people have moved to centralised silos like Twitter. The reason? Too many competing standards. The story of RSS teaches us that a better, more open Web will come from getting better at working together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/a3mm4z/the-rise-and-demise-of-rss&quot;&gt;The Rise and Demise of RSS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-semantic-web-identity-crisis-in-search-of-the-trivialities-that-never-were&quot;&gt;The Semantic Web identity crisis: in search of the trivialities that never were&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a similar vein to the story of RSS, Ruben Verborgh talks about the last two decades of research into the Semantic Web – and how it hasn’t really changed the world much. The dream was big, the vision was crystal clear, but through lack of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eating_your_own_dog_food&quot;&gt;dogfooding&lt;/a&gt; the dream hasn’t been delivered. But if semantic technologies can be brough out of the research space and into the world of product development…who knows?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://ruben.verborgh.org/articles/the-semantic-web-identity-crisis/&quot;&gt;The Semantic Web identity crisis: in search of the trivialities that never were&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;data-as-institutional-memory&quot;&gt;Data as institutional memory&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another excellent post about standards, from Adam, plumping for collaboratively developed standards as part of a system, not just a by-product of policy and legislation. ‘Fix the plumbing by identifying the leaks’ rang in my head for a couple of days after reading this, it’s a great analogy. Great stuff on designing data as infrastructure in the 21st century. (Adam running his mouth in the pub is something I enjoy being around, it produces gems like this.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@chairlord/data-as-institutional-memory-ad5367da2194&quot;&gt;Data as institutional memory&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-data-is-never-raw&quot;&gt;Why Data Is Never Raw&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t believe we should aim for data-driven futures because it renders human decisions as useless. Instead we should be data-informed, reading metrics and measures to inform our decisions. But it’s worth remembering that data is never raw: the schema by which you collect and read data goes some way to defining how you’ll interpret it. In &lt;em&gt;The New Atlantis&lt;/em&gt;, Nick Barrowman talks about the seductive myth of information free of human judgment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thenewatlantis.com/publications/why-data-is-never-raw&quot;&gt;Why Data Is Never Raw&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;unicorns-ontologies-and-how-the-mind-organizes-the-world&quot;&gt;Unicorns, Ontologies and How the Mind Organizes the World&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world of structured data was a right headf**k when I first joined Porism. Since there’s much chatter about ontologies, taxonomies, registers and other aspects of semantic technologies at work now, I always send this article to anyone starting out. Who knew a story about Marco Polo would help frame it so well?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://thesnipermind.com/blog/unicorns-ontologies-and-how-the-mind-organizes-the-world.html&quot;&gt;Unicorns, Ontologies and How the Mind Organizes the World&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;just-good-stories&quot;&gt;Just good stories&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;were-not-leaving-this-bar-until-weve-come-up-with-such-a-great-idea-that-i-cant-sack-you&quot;&gt;“We’re not leaving this bar until we’ve come up with such a great idea that I can’t sack you”&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story of how BBC iPlayer came about because of a drunken brainstorm as told by Tony Ageh, who was the project director for the thing. It’s funny and uplifting and wonderfully down-to-earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/storythings-ltd/we-re-not-leaving-this-bar-until-we-ve-come-up-with-such-a-great-idea-that-i-can-t-sack-you-b12ddfd53fa8&quot;&gt;“We’re not leaving this bar until we’ve come up with such a great idea that I can’t sack you”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-william-gibson-keeps-his-science-fiction-real&quot;&gt;How William Gibson Keeps His Science Fiction Real&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;William Gibson invented the word ‘cyberspace’ and, along with it, the cyberpunk movement and everything that inspired. I grew up on &lt;em&gt;The Matrix&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Blade Runner&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Johnny Mnemonic&lt;/em&gt; and the video game &lt;em&gt;Deus Ex&lt;/em&gt;, so it’s pleasing to hear how the books that inspired those worlds – beginning with Gibson’s debut &lt;em&gt;Neuromancer&lt;/em&gt; – came together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2019/12/16/how-william-gibson-keeps-his-science-fiction-real&quot;&gt;How William Gibson Keeps His Science Fiction Real&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;it-wasnt-all-about-drugs&quot;&gt;“It wasn’t all about drugs”&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By talking to teenagers about the acid house movement of the 1980s, Jeremy Deller managed to explore the period and what it was really all about, without falling on the obvious answer of drugs. This is a good interview about his documentary, &lt;em&gt;Everybody in the Place: an Incomplete History of Britain 1984–92&lt;/em&gt;, but you should definitely also &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/m000777d&quot;&gt;watch the doc&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://theface.com/culture/jeremy-deller-interview-everybody-in-the-place-an-incomplete-history-of-britain-1984-1992&quot;&gt;“It wasn’t all about drugs”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-brexit-warnings-to-be-found-in-sheep-grazing-in-a-london-park&quot;&gt;The Brexit Warnings to Be Found in Sheep Grazing in a London Park&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An overlapping of stories about the commons, Boudica, Hampstead Heath, and thoughts on Brexit back in September. (I mostly like it for the agricultural experiment and the archeology, but there’s something in there for politicos too.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;link&quot;&gt;The Brexit Warnings to Be Found in Sheep Grazing in a London Park&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-real-life-ali-g&quot;&gt;The real-life Ali G&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can’t remember why I came across this story about Tim Westwood but it’s absolutely cracking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/theguardian/2000/nov/01/features11.g22&quot;&gt;The real-life Ali G&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;in-1968-computers-got-personal&quot;&gt;In 1968, computers got personal&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story of how ‘the mother of all demos’ changed the world, moving computing from the research space to the commercial space. By helping people imagine a future in which everyone had a computer, we now do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;http://theconversation.com/in-1968-computers-got-personal-how-the-mother-of-all-demos-changed-the-world-101654&quot;&gt;In 1968, computers got personal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;If anyone has stratified the eras of government transformation, digital and beyond, please do let me know! &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://visitmy.website/2019/12/14/reading-list-picks-of-2019/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://visitmy.website/2019/12/14/reading-list-picks-of-2019/</guid>
        
        <category>Blogroll</category>
        
        <category>Popular</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Revivalist aesthetic: musical discoveries from 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last year I put together &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/user/renegatus/playlist/7kFVj9Y23ABBFZKpho2kTb?si=TRb7A_7tS26LV8yLESGqjg&quot;&gt;a playlist of music I’d loved or first listened to in 2018&lt;/a&gt; and, genre-wise, it was relatively varied. Beats, jazz-funk, rock, club heaters, hip-hop and some essential bass music. This year’s list, however, is quite different to that. It’s a playlist of songs that are mostly all the same, to be honest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2019 has been the year of the revivalist sound, with young producers harkening back to the days of 1990s rave with pumping modern tributes. The stand-out release for me has been Soundbwoy Killah’s &lt;em&gt;Halcyon Daze&lt;/em&gt;, an LP ‘suffused…with the heady fug of rave memories and long nights in the dance’ (&lt;a href=&quot;https://bleep.com/release/140146-soundbwoy-killah-halcyon-daze&quot;&gt;as told by Bleep&lt;/a&gt;). They’re tunes that make you want to go raving again, even if your own halcyon days were 2006–2013, not the decade previous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This playlist is packed with those kinds of tunes, it reeks of nostalgia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a way, it’s a mournful playlist. Going out these days isn’t like what it used to be (*cough* old man *cough*). In reviving the warehouse rave, clubs like Printworks have mass-marketed and stripped away the original appeal: underground folklore. It’s something Burial touches on in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thewire.co.uk/in-writing/interviews/burial_unedited-transcript&quot;&gt;this interview&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;em&gt;Wire&lt;/em&gt; magazine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The UK was changing in a different direction, away from us. Maybe the feeling of the UK in clubs and stuff back then, it wasn’t as artificial, self-aware or created by the internet. It was more rumour, underground folklore. No mobile phones back then. Anyone could go into the night and they had to seek it out. Because you could see it in people, you could see it in their eyes. Those ravers were at the edge at their lives, they weren’t running ahead or falling behind, they were just right there and the tunes meant everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a time when I respected music in that way. These days I don’t give it enough dedication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then again, maybe it’s an optimistic playlist. The music I’ve listened to and loved in 2019 seems to be sounds of a remembered era, and I’m really keen to go out and hear music again. I miss it: the swaying, the lights, the sweat, the laughs. So 41 tracks remembering all that has sparked my keenness to get dancing again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, that’s enough blabbering. Here’s the playlist of tracks I discovered or loved in 2019. Listen on &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/user/renegatus/playlist/38zfJWixkV78IKP7glwFyK?si=xmdXYJcsT4qo-3CiVwusBQ&quot;&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://buymusic.club/list/and-more-discoveries-2019&quot;&gt;Bandcamp through Buy Music Club&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here’s to getting back out there. See you in the dance, front-left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tracklist&quot;&gt;Tracklist&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;#&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Title&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Artist&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Halcyon Daze&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Soundbwoy Killah&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Dream&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Robohands&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Rufige&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Lee Gamble&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Dreaming&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Jon Hassell&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Nu Spring&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;30/70&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Ai Paint&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Young Paint&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Crux&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Sporting Life&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Jazterpiece&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Dennis Bovell&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Op&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Bremer/McCoy&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;BROWN PAPER BAG&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;TOSHIO MATSUURA GROUP&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;11&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Audi A3&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;L U C Y&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Dilla Mix 1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Abstract Orchestra&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;13&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Suite Haus&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Makaya McCraven&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;14&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;ザ・ワードII - Remixed by 鳥居真道 (トリプルファイヤー)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;セキトオ・シゲオ&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;15&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;I’m ready for dancing&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Ronald Langestraat&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;16&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Mumma Don’t Tell&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Leifur James&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;17&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Sète&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Souleance&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;18&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Ball&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Duval Timothy&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;19&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Film Score&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Smith &amp;amp; Mighty&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;20&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Walworth Waltz&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Joy Orbison&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;21&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Tumblin’ (Death March)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Smith &amp;amp; Mighty&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;22&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Flyby Vfr&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Skee Mask&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;23&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Dial 274&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Skee Mask&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;24&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Black Balloons Reprise&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Flying Lotus&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;25&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Loiner Dub&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Soundbwoy Killah&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;26&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Be Ya Girl&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;KW Griff&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;27&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;RZZ&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Skee Mask&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;28&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Controlled Energy Release&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;THUGWIDOW&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;29&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Chiseler’s Rush&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Call Super &amp;amp; Parris&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;30&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;I Hate When People Make Tracks Like This&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Jimmy Edgar&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;31&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Olbass All Bass 004 (140 BPM)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Vegyn&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;32&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;iii’s Front&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Overmono&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;33&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;02-52-03&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;RP Boo&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;34&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Under the Influence&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Soundbwoy Killah&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;35&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Kotos&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Mala&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;36&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Do it Again&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Shinichiro Yokota&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;37&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Foxxy&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Cassius&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;38&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Glass Eye&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Pearson Sound&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;39&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;My Future&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Loraine James&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;40&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Bullseye&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Sully&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;41&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;It Ain’t Love&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Rahsaan Patterson&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://visitmy.website/2019/12/01/revivalist-aesthetic-musical-discoveries-2019/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://visitmy.website/2019/12/01/revivalist-aesthetic-musical-discoveries-2019/</guid>
        
        <category>Blogroll</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Jam London 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For the past few years I’ve been going to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jamlondon.io/events/&quot;&gt;Jam London&lt;/a&gt;, a product and design conference sharing the stories behind great products. It’s great to hear from product and design leaders from across the world, and I’ve always learned a thing or two that I take back to my practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s some rough notes I made on my phone during the talks, in case it’s helpful for others. The full line-up is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jamlondon.io/events/jam-london-2019&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. The talks from Jamie Nicholson, Chelsea Bullock and Susana Lopes were best for me that day. Lots about navigating uncertainty, trust, empathy and failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;building-with-stories&quot;&gt;Building with Stories&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;jeff-gardner-intercom&quot;&gt;Jeff Gardner, Intercom&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stories the best way to organise people around a single idea. But why do we think we’re not capable of building stories? Here’s some tips on building better stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The type of story we’re telling is a business parable, driving someone’s behaviour to reach an outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good stories must have&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a clear message&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;emotionally engaging&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;simple enough to be retold&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A story is an idea virus, and good stories are contagious. It can be easy to make a story short, quicker to tell, retell and understand. Make stories short.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Focus on feelings, rather than details. How do you want the audience to feel?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adapt to your audience. Comedians spend lots of time seeing jokes bomb to understand which will work. You need to try to be good. Saying ‘Anyway, it’s a long story’ can help you understand whether anyone wants to hear it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make storytelling a practice, learn from what doesn’t work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Start with the point&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set the scene, quickly&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use dialogue&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Surprise!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Restate the point&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of all the animals, we’re the only ones that live in a dual reality: the world in front of us and the world in our heads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;building-trust-with-research-teams&quot;&gt;Building trust with research teams&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;chelsea-bullock-mailchimp&quot;&gt;Chelsea Bullock, Mailchimp&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team dynamics are different when teams have trust between the members. New teams have lower trust; teams with trust move fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Worked on a project based on a VP’s idea with a team that had high trust. Tried to reframe the feature proposal but kept running into dead ends, it wasn’t going to work. They were asked how to do it, not whether to do it or not. Users didn’t fundamentally see the problem so the feature didn’t need it. High trust team only spiralled for a while and they quickly pivoted to saying ‘This won’t work’ and the company was grateful, saved money and time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mutual trust meant they could move from discovery to validation to learning very quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you know if you’re working in a trust vacuum?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No one knows what you’re doing there&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Deliverables feel safer than learnings&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Doubts and suspicions about motivations and goals of team-mates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trust gap can cause problems. Build empathy and trust to move forward together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stage Zero collaboration: or, where to start when you don’t know how to begin. First step in building trust between research partners is asking ‘What decision will these findings enable you to make?’ Gives you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;clarity of mission&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;buy-in on the stakes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;alignment in prioritisation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Successfully answering that requires&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;curiosity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;vulnerability &amp;amp; compassion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;clear vision&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stories clarify our expectations of each other and acknowledge the value we all bring to the work. It energises teams and renews trust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s really easy to keep our heads down and deliver, but we should turn these into collective stories. Show &amp;amp; tell often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trust over tools. Tools and frameworks are easy, but understanding and communication is most useful. Empathy.
￼
Trust is better for team health. If there’s low trust, establish clarity of mission and get leadership involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/IMG_1836.png&quot; alt=&quot;Building trust with your research team&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-research-inspires-new-products&quot;&gt;How research inspires new products&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;jamie-nicholson-instagram&quot;&gt;Jamie Nicholson, Instagram&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Design for and with people. Understand needs, desires and wants. Do research early, not after building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Testing ideas and getting feedback is very important, but it’s easy to get lost and not move the needle (meet business objectives). What’s the problem you’re solving? How is that part of people’s lives?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moved from ‘Why do you use Instagram?’ to ‘How do you make friends?’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looked at how the different features fit into making friendships. You might like an acquaintance’s photo, but you’ll send a DM to a best friend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ask big questions. (How do they want to feel? Uncover behaviours and mental models, to see how this things sits in someone’s life.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get beneath the surface of what is said, people don’t know what they want. Go deep to find the magic they need.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Talk to extremes. Start at the edges and move inwards. Don’t go for average behaviours.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personas are hard, you can’t design for the average with millions of users. Instead tell the stories of people you find that represent a broader group of people. It drives empathy in the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;agile-for-everybody-everybody-hates-agile&quot;&gt;Agile for Everybody, Everybody Hates Agile&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;matt-lemay-sudden-compass&quot;&gt;Matt LeMay, Sudden Compass&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agile is a completely made-up thing that 17 people dreamed up on a ski weekend, so &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;¯\_(ツ)_/¯&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agile methods ask people to think and, frankly, that’s a hard sell. So be brave, get started and change the way you’re working until it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-scale-globally&quot;&gt;How to scale globally&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;kaarel-kuddu-transferwise&quot;&gt;Kaarel Kuddu, Transferwise&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Launched in a country based on World Bank data. Didn’t work because they didn’t know their customers and how TransferWise fit into their lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ran an experiment to see if people would choose currencies to send. Got some data, saw demand for currencies, launched those and tracked uptake. No correlation between demand and uptake because product experience wasn’t approached in the same way in different countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;failure&quot;&gt;Failure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;maryam-mazraei-autopsy&quot;&gt;Maryam Mazraei, Autopsy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4 years of work ended in failure, which got her interested in taking lessons from failure. Survivor bias creates problems for people who follow the ‘playbook’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at the common components of failure help you to spot patterns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data from Crunchbase, OpenCorporates, Companies House, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;keep-pace-master-product-at-bmw-100-years-old&quot;&gt;Keep pace, master product at BMW (100 years old)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;sabrina-rzepka-bmw&quot;&gt;Sabrina Rzepka, BMW&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working with cars different: no feature flags, no Build-Measure-Learn, no fail fast. Features have many dependencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make a vision visible&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gain speed with a co-pilot&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Focus on the essentials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;you-didnt-fail-your-product-did&quot;&gt;You didn’t fail, your product did&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;susana-lopes-onfido&quot;&gt;Susana Lopes, Onfido&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Behind pristine LinkedIn profiles are our bruised egos and failed projects. They’re lurking there and we never talk about our shadow careers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grew up with the ‘Failure is not an option’ mantra but it turned her into a dictator. Worked at Huddle, they had quarterly commitments for sales people, things they’d deliver on time that didn’t exist yet. Made her think that success = shipping on time. Efficiency theatre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By thinking that failure was not an option, she chose the easiest route to success - instead of actually delivering value to customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fear of failure creates high pressure and clouded judgement. You need to release that pressure to succeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Swapped ‘Failure is not an option’ for ‘Fail fast, fail early’, de-risking aspects of the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spoke to customers using web product on Android to collect problems, hoping to rebuild the Android app and convert those people. De-risked problem and value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;De-risked usability. De-risked feasibility. Kept shipping and growing, de-risking beforehand…until the numbers stalled. Value plateaued.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Didn’t validate that the problem existed for enough people, enough of the time. But blamed herself. Emotional resilience held her back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But she didn’t fail, the product did. And she learned and can do better next time. Separate self-worth from product-worth, maybe by creating product success metrics and personal success metrics. Creates emotional distance by being product’s worst critic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/IMG_1838.png&quot; alt=&quot;Failing forward&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://visitmy.website/2019/11/02/jam-2019/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://visitmy.website/2019/11/02/jam-2019/</guid>
        
        <category>Blogroll</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Reading List Picks of 2018</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been a heck of a year. I got to fulfill a teenage dream and start working on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk&quot;&gt;an important and much-used website&lt;/a&gt;, which got me thinking about product management, people, work and the World Wide Web more than  I did last year. Here’s a bunch of articles and blog posts that piqued my interest throughout 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-build-a-low-tech-website&quot;&gt;How to Build a Low-tech Website?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Low-tech Magazine looks at the sustainability of the modern world and its practices. They decided to practice what they preach by making their website run entirely on solar power, using web design techniques to reduce energy consumption and a self-built solar power bank to run it all – no data centres and CDNs in sight. Though it occasionally goes offline when there’s not enough power, the article really got me thinking about the ‘always on’ nature of the Web and how that’s quite wasteful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2018/09/how-to-build-a-lowtech-website.html&quot;&gt;How to Build a Low-tech Website?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-bullshit-web&quot;&gt;The Bullshit Web&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a similar vein to Low-tech Magazine, Nick Heer wrote about the ballooning bullshit of data on the Web and the wastefulness of filling your 17MB/s internet connection with ads. It’s an essay on what the Web was meant to be, and what it has become; and how the Information Superhighway could benefit from those of us working on it to take more responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://pxlnv.com/blog/bullshit-web/&quot;&gt;The Bullshit Web&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-cognition-crisis&quot;&gt;The Cognition Crisis&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Waking up and checking your phone. Scrolling through Facebook while the telly’s on. Notifications causing drivers to kill people. Adam Gazzaley argues that ‘our constant engagement with technology interferes with the pursuit of other behaviors critical for maintaining a healthy mind’, and it caused me to turn on Do Not Disturb when at work. We have natural animal minds that are being pushed to the edge by the environment we’ve built around them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/s/futurehuman/the-cognition-crisis-a1482e889fcb&quot;&gt;The Cognition Crisis&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-principles-that-make-me-a-better-product-manager&quot;&gt;The principles that make me a better product manager&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there’s one thing that’s central to the practice of product management, it’s a set of principles one can call on in any situation. A good principle can keep everyone on course but also help point the way forward in unfamiliar waters. Ross Ferguson left us with seven principles before he was poached by the Canadians, and they’ve really helped me in my first year at Government Digital Service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@rossferg/the-principles-that-make-me-a-better-product-manager-9e50814d184f&quot;&gt;The principles that make me a better product manager&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thinking-about-slos&quot;&gt;Thinking about SLOs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working out how to maintain and operate a behemoth like GOV.UK was pretty daunting when I joined Platform Health. Adopting a Service Level Objective and thinking about how we manage technical solutions from a users-first perspective has been massively helpful. I’m really grateful that &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/emilylabram&quot;&gt;Emily&lt;/a&gt; posted this by Andrew Suffield – one-time Site Reliability Engineer at Google – and for all her work on spreading SLO thinking at GDS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@asuffield/thinking-about-slos-64841737d1ed&quot;&gt;Thinking about SLOs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;teams-from-scratch--part-1-psychological-safety&quot;&gt;Teams from Scratch – Part 1: Psychological Safety&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building a culture where asking questions and admitting gaps in knowledge is OK can be hard, but this piece popped up serendipitously around the time I was doing a lot of thinking on team-building. It turned out that Alex worked at Unruly, an adtech company which shares our office building, and we’ve been meeting for coffee ever since!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@probablyfine/teams-from-scratch-part-1-psychological-safety-ea43d46cdbc6&quot;&gt;Teams from Scratch – Part 1: Psychological Safety&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-did-privacy-come-to-be-enshrined-as-a-human-right&quot;&gt;How did privacy come to be enshrined as a human right?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this year of our Lord, 2018, when the General Data Protection Regulation was enshrined in law, no doubt many of us were thinking &lt;em&gt;Why on earth are we going through all this pain?&lt;/em&gt; Preparing for GDPR was a huge undertaking, and despite the boring spreadsheets and confusing issues around compliance, I think it’s largely a Good Thing. This series by Projects by IF traces the history of our right to privacy and the role of regulation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/if-policy-research/how-did-privacy-come-to-be-enshrined-as-a-human-right-286d97344008&quot;&gt;How did privacy come to be enshrined as a human right?&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;microdosing-isnt-a-shortcut-to-professional-success&quot;&gt;Microdosing Isn’t a Shortcut to Professional Success&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being employed in Tech, with working weeks called ‘sprints’, can often feel like you’re &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; running a race, and open plan offices can dwindle your focus. Some people turn to microdosing – taking small amounts of psychoactive drugs – to find a balance, but Erica Avey argues that perhaps we should change the way we work, not our biology. This article applies to coffee as much as it does to LSD, in my eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/s/story/microdosing-lsd-made-me-quit-my-job-ba425aa86fcb&quot;&gt;Microdosing Isn’t a Shortcut to Professional Success&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;weeknotes-styles&quot;&gt;Weeknotes styles&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year I started writing weeknotes, a weekly reflection on my working week, and I’ve found the practice really beneficial. It’s like a personal retrospective, giving you a chance to package up the week and move on, making improvements. I recommend it to a lot of people I meet, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/stamanfar&quot;&gt;Sam&lt;/a&gt; wrote this piece on the different styles the &lt;a href=&quot;https://weeknot.es&quot;&gt;Web of Weeknotes&lt;/a&gt; community uses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://weeknot.es/weeknote-styles-61d957e58a4a&quot;&gt;Weeknotes styles&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;this-isnt-for-everyone&quot;&gt;This isn’t for everyone&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What surprised me most when I joined GDS was that many of our products didn’t have defined user personas. Nor did we say who we wouldn’t build things for. Not all users are equal. The mindset of building for everyone is helpful in not excluding certain groups, but it can widen the scope of a product too much. The Parliament Data team, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/fantasticlife&quot;&gt;Michael&lt;/a&gt; in particular, have been good in acknowledging that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;http://smethur.st/posts/176135868&quot;&gt;This isn’t for everyone&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;democratic-technical-debt&quot;&gt;Democratic technical debt&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digital government has surged forth leaving improved services in its wake. But how much of the enhancements are only surface-deep? ‘If you don’t consider what the long term impact of how you build something is, you’re accruing democratic technical debt,’ author Alex Blandford says. While also positing that terrific idea, Alex also points out that, well, government has been a bit shit at providing the research it has conducted. A few blog posts ain’t enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@blangry/democratic-technical-debt-ff2f119cbeed&quot;&gt;Democratic technical debt&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;building-personal-resilience-or-how-to-avoid-burnout&quot;&gt;Building personal resilience (or how to avoid burnout)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year has been hectic, and it’s possible for work to become all-consuming if you’re not careful. What helped me avoid that was to draw a line between my professional and personal lives: I used weeknotes to package up the week, and I used personal time to replenish my mind and soul. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/pippapeasland&quot;&gt;Pippa&lt;/a&gt; takes a great perspective on how to do that in this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@philippa.peasland_69295/building-personal-resilience-or-how-to-avoid-burnout-d6d71ee7be75&quot;&gt;Building personal resilience (or how to avoid burnout)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;targeted-advertising-is-ruining-the-internet-and-breaking-the-world-and-we-should-replace-facebook-with-personal-websites&quot;&gt;Targeted Advertising Is Ruining the Internet and Breaking the World, and We Should Replace Facebook With Personal Websites&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In March, I stopped using Facebook to see whether I’d miss it. It wasn’t a problem at all, in fact there’s not a single feature I longed for, so I deleted my account. That’s mostly been driven by their abysmal record for privacy in recent months and their involvement in the Cambridge Analytica atrocity. I’ve read countless articles on Facebook this year, but these two stand out. One shows us how advertising has been a misplaced driver for social media firms, and the other reminds us how the Web worked before the 2.0 giants took over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/xwjden/targeted-advertising-is-ruining-the-internet-and-breaking-the-world&quot;&gt;Targeted Advertising Is Ruining the Internet and Breaking the World&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/vbanny/we-should-replace-facebook-with-personal-websites&quot;&gt;We Should Replace Facebook With Personal Websites&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;this-is-how-we-workgive-or-take&quot;&gt;This is how we work…give or take&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jukesie&quot;&gt;Matt Jukes&lt;/a&gt; is a legend of the civic tech space, a dynamo of humble magnificence with a Bristol accent – an honest, friendly, earnest kind of bloke. So of course he wrote an open piece on how he works, which caused people from all across the public sector (and others) to write one too. It’s a fascinating to read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@jukesie/this-is-how-we-work-give-or-take-6c8964cac85f&quot;&gt;This is how we work…give or take&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;empowered-product-teams&quot;&gt;Empowered Product Teams&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog post covers much of Marty Cagan’s talk when he visited us in September. It’s a long read but it’s absolutely essential for organisations scaling up, past the startup mindset. It reminds us that qualities of leadership can be better than management, and that great teams are full of ordinary people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://svpg.com/empowered-product-teams/&quot;&gt;Empowered Product Teams&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://visitmy.website/2018/12/23/reading-list-picks-of-2018/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://visitmy.website/2018/12/23/reading-list-picks-of-2018/</guid>
        
        <category>Blogroll</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>This is how I work…give or take</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dasbarrett&quot;&gt;Dan&lt;/a&gt; wanted to see how I work, so here’s what I do, based on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jukesie&quot;&gt;Jukesie’s&lt;/a&gt; rip-off of the Lifehacker ‘How I Work’ series. Other public service folk have written about &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@jukesie/this-is-how-we-work-give-or-take-6c8964cac85f&quot;&gt;how they work&lt;/a&gt; too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;: London, UK.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Current gig&lt;/strong&gt;: Associate product manager, Government Digital Service.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Current mobile device&lt;/strong&gt;: Samsung J5 for work, iPhone 8 for percy.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Current computer&lt;/strong&gt;: MacBook Air 13” for work. Mac Mini at home. Some hobby Raspberry Pis and a PC too.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;One word that best describes how you work&lt;/strong&gt;: Metered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;first-of-all-tell-us-a-little-about-your-background-and-how-you-got-to-where-you-are-today&quot;&gt;First of all, tell us a little about your background and how you got to where you are today&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Liked books and computers growing up. Spent a huge portion of my teenage years in my bedroom, tinkering on the Web or with computers. But I also enjoyed writing stories. Aged 16, I decided to focus on my Literature studies instead of Information Technology. It seemed to have…more prestige.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did my A-levels, went to Bath Spa Uni to study Creative Writing. Bought a Mac to stop me playing video games. It worked, and I had a lot of fun. The course was excellent with great teachers – check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bathspa.ac.uk/schools/liberal-arts/interest-areas/creative-writing/creative-writing-publications/&quot;&gt;some of the authors who’ve also studied at Bath Spa&lt;/a&gt; – and I had my sights set on a career in publishing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Graduated. Spent the next year continuing cheffing, then quit to get some work experience and make the most of my degree. Spent two weeks as a managing editorial assistant at Vintage Publishing (part of Random House) and was asked back for another week. A few months later, there’s an open position as an editorial assistant and they ask me to apply. Incredibly, I get it and dive into the literary publishing world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do that for 9 months. Move on to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.penguin.co.uk/company/publishers/vintage/jonathan-cape.html&quot;&gt;Jonathan Cape&lt;/a&gt;, attend a Booker Prize ceremony in my first week. It’s quite glitzy, maybe too glitzy, especially for a working class boy from Wolverhampton. I get the chance to work with some of the most eminent, prolific literary authors in the world. They even let me commission &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.penguin.co.uk/books/109/1093783/finally-my-ambulance/9780099575870.html&quot;&gt;a book of short stories&lt;/a&gt;. But I feel massively out of my depth and haven’t been to Oxbridge, like most others at my level. Self-doubt sets in. Work is naught but toil. I grow tired of the sausage factory. I quit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so I have a breakdown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The clouds pass after 6 months and I get a job at NOW TV, which was just starting out. See Agile and software development in action. Turns out that’s quite glitzy too, except I didn’t know that at school. IT is kind of cool now. &lt;em&gt;Hmm, maybe I could do tech after all.&lt;/em&gt; After some time in Operations, they initiate a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/transfers-takeovers&quot;&gt;TUPE process&lt;/a&gt; for an entire department and I need to find other work. &lt;a href=&quot;http://porism.com&quot;&gt;Porism&lt;/a&gt; has an opening for someone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I focus on increasing engagement and use of &lt;a href=&quot;http://lginformplus.local.gov.uk&quot;&gt;LG Inform Plus&lt;/a&gt;, then get the chance to redesign and launch a new version of &lt;a href=&quot;https://ecasework.com&quot;&gt;eCasework&lt;/a&gt;. We spent a year on that before it went live. Take-up wasn’t good. I wrestled with marketing techniques, sales, developing some features and trying to talk to the few users we had. Wasn’t really sure what I was doing. It was…enjoyable, but also like banging my head against a brick wall. Repeatedly. Every day. Because I’m leading myself blind. (However, I also learn some cool stuff about open data, local government and generally learn tons from &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MikeThacker&quot;&gt;Mike&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explaining my anguish to a friend, he suggests that I’m kind of doing product management. I read a few blogs, try out the techniques, and they work. &lt;em&gt;Hmm, maybe I could do tech after all.&lt;/em&gt; Attending the product management course at General Assembly gives me new skills. We start to grow eCasework and its user base. We develop features that people love. But I’m a bit hungry for more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apply for a job working on GOV.UK. They offer it to me. I’m overjoyed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now I’m just really, really happy. I’m at home. I’m back in my bedroom, tinkering on the Web and with computers, on a piece of the national infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;take-us-through-a-recent-workday&quot;&gt;Take us through a recent workday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a T-shaped structure to my week which I try to stick to. Mornings are for product thinking, writing cards or catching up on important emails, except on Wednesdays when I’ll meet &lt;a href=&quot;undefined&quot;&gt;Alex&lt;/a&gt; for coffee. Then it’s a catch-up with Delivery Manager and Tech Lead, followed by stand-up with the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Tuesdays and Wednesdays, the rest of the day is either meetings, team ceremonies or community meet-ups with other product managers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mondays, Thursdays and Fridays are a bit lighter: product thinking, analysing data and trends, and chats with other specialists, often dappled with the odd meeting here and there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The details of what actually happens can be found in &lt;a href=&quot;https://weeknot.es/@stevenjmesser&quot;&gt;my weeknotes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-apps-gadgets-or-tools-cant-you-live-without&quot;&gt;What apps, gadgets or tools can’t you live without?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://slack.com&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; Reminders, my philosopher’s stone at work. With simple commands, I can remind myself or a colleague to do something. Need I say more? Since I have the app on my iPhone too, I can capture those work-related thoughts that spring up in the shower, at dinner or when I’m on holiday. It gets things out of my head, and only brings them back when needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I’ve been using &lt;a href=&quot;https://getpocket.com&quot;&gt;Pocket&lt;/a&gt; a fair amount to save blogs to read. Medium’s Reading List also comes in handy, but I’m trying to move away from the platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, too. It’s the app I use most. To both fill time productively and waste it. &lt;a href=&quot;https://mysocialsummary.com&quot;&gt;My Social Summary&lt;/a&gt; is great for catching up on Twitter without needing to scroll through Twitter. It looks for the most engaging tweets from lists you’ve built and sends you a daily digest. Definitely worth £3 a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve really taken to Post-it notes as a to-do list. I tried Trello but you’re not always able to add cards in meetings or ceremonies. Post-its are always at hand in GDS, so I can quickly capture sudden thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Here’s some &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@stevenjmesser/my-bootstrapped-stack-dca24da282cd&quot;&gt;stuff I’ve used at work&lt;/a&gt; before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-your-best-shortcut-or-life-hack&quot;&gt;What’s your best shortcut or life hack?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have to do something three times, automate it. If you can’t automate it, find a way to reduce the toil. You’ll immediately create more time to spend on things that really need it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;take-us-through-an-interesting-unusual-or-finicky-process-you-have-in-place-at-work&quot;&gt;Take us through an interesting, unusual, or finicky process you have in place at work&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you forget your work pass, you can’t get through many of the (mostly glass) doors. You end up staring forlornly at the people on the other side, who don’t know whether to let you in &lt;em&gt;sans&lt;/em&gt; ID. Sometimes several people walk past before you’re permitted to exit your dimension of uselessness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven’t worked out how to capitalise on this yet. It’s &lt;em&gt;a bit&lt;/em&gt; like a cigarette break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-do-you-keep-track-of-what-you-have-to-do&quot;&gt;How do you keep track of what you have to do?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like I said earlier, Slack Reminders and Post-it notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-your-favourite-side-project&quot;&gt;What’s your favourite side project?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m currently playing with &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; to refresh my &lt;a href=&quot;https://visitmy.website&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; and move blog posts away from Medium. But I’m also running out of kimchi so will have to make some more of that soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-are-you-currently-reading-or-what-do-you-recommend-to-read&quot;&gt;What are you currently reading, or what do you recommend to read?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m reading &lt;em&gt;Throwing Rocks at the Google Bus&lt;/em&gt; by Douglas Rushkoff for non-fiction, and &lt;em&gt;Memoirs of Hadrian&lt;/em&gt; by Marguerite Yourcenar for fiction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;who-else-would-you-like-to-see-answer-these-questions&quot;&gt;Who else would you like to see answer these questions?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MikeThacker&quot;&gt;Mike&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Ellayanor&quot;&gt;Ellie&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/pr0bablyfine&quot;&gt;Alex&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/johncutlefish&quot;&gt;John&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/emilylabram&quot;&gt;Emily&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/femkesvs&quot;&gt;Femke&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-the-best-advice-youve-ever-received&quot;&gt;What’s the best advice you’ve ever received?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘You can do whatever you want in life, as long as you don’t hurt anyone.’ Oh, and: ‘Work is just a way to pay the bills, but it helps if you enjoy it.’ Both from my dad.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://visitmy.website/2018/11/17/this-is-how-i-work-give-or-take/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://visitmy.website/2018/11/17/this-is-how-i-work-give-or-take/</guid>
        
        <category>Blogroll</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
