<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Steve Messer // Product manager</title>
    <description>Product person, GOV.UK, Government Digital Service. Web enthusiast, working in the open. Black Country boy living in London, UK.</description>
    <link>https://visitmy.website</link>
    <atom:link href="https://visitmy.website/feed.blogroll.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 08:25:30 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 08:25:30 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Reading List Picks of 2018</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been a heck of a year. I got to fulfill a teenage dream and start working on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk&quot;&gt;an important and much-used website&lt;/a&gt;, which got me thinking about product management, people, work and the World Wide Web more than  I did last year. Here’s a bunch of articles and blog posts that piqued my interest throughout 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to receive articles like this in your inbox every week, sign up to my &lt;a href=&quot;https://tinyletter.com/stevenjmesser&quot;&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-build-a-low-tech-website&quot;&gt;How to Build a Low-tech Website?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Low-tech Magazine looks at the sustainability of the modern world and its practices. They decided to practice what they preach by making their website run entirely on solar power, using web design techniques to reduce energy consumption and a self-built solar power bank to run it all – no data centres and CDNs in sight. Though it occasionally goes offline when there’s not enough power, the article really got me thinking about the ‘always on’ nature of the Web and how that’s quite wasteful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2018/09/how-to-build-a-lowtech-website.html&quot;&gt;How to Build a Low-tech Website?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-bullshit-web&quot;&gt;The Bullshit Web&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a similar vein to Low-tech Magazine, Nick Heer wrote about the ballooning bullshit of data on the Web and the wastefulness of filling your 17MB/s internet connection with ads. It’s an essay on what the Web was meant to be, and what it has become; and how the Information Superhighway could benefit from those of us working on it to take more responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://pxlnv.com/blog/bullshit-web/&quot;&gt;The Bullshit Web&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-cognition-crisis&quot;&gt;The Cognition Crisis&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Waking up and checking your phone. Scrolling through Facebook while the telly’s on. Notifications causing drivers to kill people. Adam Gazzaley argues that ‘our constant engagement with technology interferes with the pursuit of other behaviors critical for maintaining a healthy mind’, and it caused me to turn on Do Not Disturb when at work. We have natural animal minds that are being pushed to the edge by the environment we’ve built around them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/s/futurehuman/the-cognition-crisis-a1482e889fcb&quot;&gt;The Cognition Crisis&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-principles-that-make-me-a-better-product-manager&quot;&gt;The principles that make me a better product manager&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there’s one thing that’s central to the practice of product management, it’s a set of principles one can call on in any situation. A good principle can keep everyone on course but also help point the way forward in unfamiliar waters. Ross Ferguson left us with seven principles before he was poached by the Canadians, and they’ve really helped me in my first year at Government Digital Service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@rossferg/the-principles-that-make-me-a-better-product-manager-9e50814d184f&quot;&gt;The principles that make me a better product manager&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thinking-about-slos&quot;&gt;Thinking about SLOs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working out how to maintain and operate a behemoth like GOV.UK was pretty daunting when I joined Platform Health. Adopting a Service Level Objective and thinking about how we manage technical solutions from a users-first perspective has been massively helpful. I’m really grateful that &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/emilylabram&quot;&gt;Emily&lt;/a&gt; posted this by Andrew Suffield – one-time Site Reliability Engineer at Google – and for all her work on spreading SLO thinking at GDS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@asuffield/thinking-about-slos-64841737d1ed&quot;&gt;Thinking about SLOs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;teams-from-scratch--part-1-psychological-safety&quot;&gt;Teams from Scratch – Part 1: Psychological Safety&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building a culture where asking questions and admitting gaps in knowledge is OK can be hard, but this piece popped up serendipitously around the time I was doing a lot of thinking on team-building. It turned out that Alex worked at Unruly, an adtech company which shares our office building, and we’ve been meeting for coffee ever since!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@probablyfine/teams-from-scratch-part-1-psychological-safety-ea43d46cdbc6&quot;&gt;Teams from Scratch – Part 1: Psychological Safety&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-did-privacy-come-to-be-enshrined-as-a-human-right&quot;&gt;How did privacy come to be enshrined as a human right?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this year of our Lord, 2018, when the General Data Protection Regulation was enshrined in law, no doubt many of us were thinking &lt;em&gt;Why on earth are we going through all this pain?&lt;/em&gt; Preparing for GDPR was a huge undertaking, and despite the boring spreadsheets and confusing issues around compliance, I think it’s largely a Good Thing. This series by Projects by IF traces the history of our right to privacy and the role of regulation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/if-policy-research/how-did-privacy-come-to-be-enshrined-as-a-human-right-286d97344008&quot;&gt;How did privacy come to be enshrined as a human right?&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;microdosing-isnt-a-shortcut-to-professional-success&quot;&gt;Microdosing Isn’t a Shortcut to Professional Success&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being employed in Tech, with working weeks called ‘sprints’, can often feel like you’re &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; running a race, and open plan offices can dwindle your focus. Some people turn to microdosing – taking small amounts of psychoactive drugs – to find a balance, but Erica Avey argues that perhaps we should change the way we work, not our biology. This article applies to coffee as much as it does to LSD, in my eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/s/story/microdosing-lsd-made-me-quit-my-job-ba425aa86fcb&quot;&gt;Microdosing Isn’t a Shortcut to Professional Success&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;weeknotes-styles&quot;&gt;Weeknotes styles&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year I started writing weeknotes, a weekly reflection on my working week, and I’ve found the practice really beneficial. It’s like a personal retrospective, giving you a chance to package up the week and move on, making improvements. I recommend it to a lot of people I meet, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/stamanfar&quot;&gt;Sam&lt;/a&gt; wrote this piece on the different styles the &lt;a href=&quot;https://weeknot.es&quot;&gt;Web of Weeknotes&lt;/a&gt; community uses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://weeknot.es/weeknote-styles-61d957e58a4a&quot;&gt;Weeknotes styles&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;this-isnt-for-everyone&quot;&gt;This isn’t for everyone&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What surprised me most when I joined GDS was that many of our products didn’t have defined user personas. Nor did we say who we wouldn’t build things for. Not all users are equal. The mindset of building for everyone is helpful in not excluding certain groups, but it can widen the scope of a product too much. The Parliament Data team, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/fantasticlife&quot;&gt;Michael&lt;/a&gt; in particular, have been good in acknowledging that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;http://smethur.st/posts/176135868&quot;&gt;This isn’t for everyone&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;democratic-technical-debt&quot;&gt;Democratic technical debt&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digital government has surged forth leaving improved services in its wake. But how much of the enhancements are only surface-deep? ‘If you don’t consider what the long term impact of how you build something is, you’re accruing democratic technical debt,’ author Alex Blandford says. While also positing that terrific idea, Alex also points out that, well, government has been a bit shit at providing the research it has conducted. A few blog posts ain’t enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@blangry/democratic-technical-debt-ff2f119cbeed&quot;&gt;Democratic technical debt&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;building-personal-resilience-or-how-to-avoid-burnout&quot;&gt;Building personal resilience (or how to avoid burnout)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year has been hectic, and it’s possible for work to become all-consuming if you’re not careful. What helped me avoid that was to draw a line between my professional and personal lives: I used weeknotes to package up the week, and I used personal time to replenish my mind and soul. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/pippapeasland&quot;&gt;Pippa&lt;/a&gt; takes a great perspective on how to do that in this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@philippa.peasland_69295/building-personal-resilience-or-how-to-avoid-burnout-d6d71ee7be75&quot;&gt;Building personal resilience (or how to avoid burnout)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;targeted-advertising-is-ruining-the-internet-and-breaking-the-world-and-we-should-replace-facebook-with-personal-websites&quot;&gt;Targeted Advertising Is Ruining the Internet and Breaking the World, and We Should Replace Facebook With Personal Websites&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In March, I stopped using Facebook to see whether I’d miss it. It wasn’t a problem at all, in fact there’s not a single feature I longed for, so I deleted my account. That’s mostly been driven by their abysmal record for privacy in recent months and their involvement in the Cambridge Analytica atrocity. I’ve read countless articles on Facebook this year, but these two stand out. One shows us how advertising has been a misplaced driver for social media firms, and the other reminds us how the Web worked before the 2.0 giants took over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/xwjden/targeted-advertising-is-ruining-the-internet-and-breaking-the-world&quot;&gt;Targeted Advertising Is Ruining the Internet and Breaking the World&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/vbanny/we-should-replace-facebook-with-personal-websites&quot;&gt;We Should Replace Facebook With Personal Websites&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;this-is-how-we-workgive-or-take&quot;&gt;This is how we work…give or take&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jukesie&quot;&gt;Matt Jukes&lt;/a&gt; is a legend of the civic tech space, a dynamo of humble magnificence with a Bristol accent – an honest, friendly, earnest kind of bloke. So of course he wrote an open piece on how he works, which caused people from all across the public sector (and others) to write one too. It’s a fascinating to read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@jukesie/this-is-how-we-work-give-or-take-6c8964cac85f&quot;&gt;This is how we work…give or take&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;empowered-product-teams&quot;&gt;Empowered Product Teams&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog post covers much of Marty Cagan’s talk when he visited us in September. It’s a long read but it’s absolutely essential for organisations scaling up, past the startup mindset. It reminds us that qualities of leadership can be better than management, and that great teams are full of ordinary people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://svpg.com/empowered-product-teams/&quot;&gt;Empowered Product Teams&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to receive articles like this in your inbox every week, sign up to my &lt;a href=&quot;https://tinyletter.com/stevenjmesser&quot;&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://visitmy.website/2018/12/23/reading-list-picks-of-2018/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://visitmy.website/2018/12/23/reading-list-picks-of-2018/</guid>
        
        <category>Blogroll</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>This is how I work…give or take</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dasbarrett&quot;&gt;Dan&lt;/a&gt; wanted to see how I work, so here’s what I do, based on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jukesie&quot;&gt;Jukesie’s&lt;/a&gt; rip-off of the Lifehacker ‘How I Work’ series. Other public service folk have written about &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@jukesie/this-is-how-we-work-give-or-take-6c8964cac85f&quot;&gt;how they work&lt;/a&gt; too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;: London, UK.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Current gig&lt;/strong&gt;: Associate product manager, Government Digital Service.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Current mobile device&lt;/strong&gt;: Samsung J5 for work, iPhone 8 for percy.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Current computer&lt;/strong&gt;: MacBook Air 13” for work. Mac Mini at home. Some hobby Raspberry Pis and a PC too.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;One word that best describes how you work&lt;/strong&gt;: Metered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;first-of-all-tell-us-a-little-about-your-background-and-how-you-got-to-where-you-are-today&quot;&gt;First of all, tell us a little about your background and how you got to where you are today&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Liked books and computers growing up. Spent a huge portion of my teenage years in my bedroom, tinkering on the Web or with computers. But I also enjoyed writing stories. Aged 16, I decided to focus on my Literature studies instead of Information Technology. It seemed to have…more prestige.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did my A-levels, went to Bath Spa Uni to study Creative Writing. Bought a Mac to stop me playing video games. It worked, and I had a lot of fun. The course was excellent with great teachers – check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bathspa.ac.uk/schools/liberal-arts/interest-areas/creative-writing/creative-writing-publications/&quot;&gt;some of the authors who’ve also studied at Bath Spa&lt;/a&gt; – and I had my sights set on a career in publishing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Graduated. Spent the next year continuing cheffing, then quit to get some work experience and make the most of my degree. Spent two weeks as a managing editorial assistant at Vintage Publishing (part of Random House) and was asked back for another week. A few months later, there’s an open position as an editorial assistant and they ask me to apply. Incredibly, I get it and dive into the literary publishing world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do that for 9 months. Move on to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.penguin.co.uk/company/publishers/vintage/jonathan-cape.html&quot;&gt;Jonathan Cape&lt;/a&gt;, attend a Booker Prize ceremony in my first week. It’s quite glitzy, maybe too glitzy, especially for a working class boy from Wolverhampton. I get the chance to work with some of the most eminent, prolific literary authors in the world. They even let me commission &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.penguin.co.uk/books/109/1093783/finally-my-ambulance/9780099575870.html&quot;&gt;a book of short stories&lt;/a&gt;. But I feel massively out of my depth and haven’t been to Oxbridge, like most others at my level. Self-doubt sets in. Work is naught but toil. I grow tired of the sausage factory. I quit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so I have a breakdown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The clouds pass after 6 months and I get a job at NOW TV, which was just starting out. See Agile and software development in action. Turns out that’s quite glitzy too, except I didn’t know that at school. IT is kind of cool now. &lt;em&gt;Hmm, maybe I could do tech after all.&lt;/em&gt; After some time in Operations, they initiate a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/transfers-takeovers&quot;&gt;TUPE process&lt;/a&gt; for an entire department and I need to find other work. &lt;a href=&quot;http://porism.com&quot;&gt;Porism&lt;/a&gt; has an opening for someone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I focus on increasing engagement and use of &lt;a href=&quot;http://lginformplus.local.gov.uk&quot;&gt;LG Inform Plus&lt;/a&gt;, then get the chance to redesign and launch a new version of &lt;a href=&quot;https://ecasework.com&quot;&gt;eCasework&lt;/a&gt;. We spent a year on that before it went live. Take-up wasn’t good. I wrestled with marketing techniques, sales, developing some features and trying to talk to the few users we had. Wasn’t really sure what I was doing. It was…enjoyable, but also like banging my head against a brick wall. Repeatedly. Every day. Because I’m leading myself blind. (However, I also learn some cool stuff about open data, local government and generally learn tons from &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MikeThacker&quot;&gt;Mike&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explaining my anguish to a friend, he suggests that I’m kind of doing product management. I read a few blogs, try out the techniques, and they work. &lt;em&gt;Hmm, maybe I could do tech after all.&lt;/em&gt; Attending the product management course at General Assembly gives me new skills. We start to grow eCasework and its user base. We develop features that people love. But I’m a bit hungry for more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apply for a job working on GOV.UK. They offer it to me. I’m overjoyed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now I’m just really, really happy. I’m at home. I’m back in my bedroom, tinkering on the Web and with computers, on a piece of the national infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;take-us-through-a-recent-workday&quot;&gt;Take us through a recent workday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a T-shaped structure to my week which I try to stick to. Mornings are for product thinking, writing cards or catching up on important emails, except on Wednesdays when I’ll meet &lt;a href=&quot;undefined&quot;&gt;Alex&lt;/a&gt; for coffee. Then it’s a catch-up with Delivery Manager and Tech Lead, followed by stand-up with the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Tuesdays and Wednesdays, the rest of the day is either meetings, team ceremonies or community meet-ups with other product managers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mondays, Thursdays and Fridays are a bit lighter: product thinking, analysing data and trends, and chats with other specialists, often dappled with the odd meeting here and there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The details of what actually happens can be found in &lt;a href=&quot;https://weeknot.es/@stevenjmesser&quot;&gt;my weeknotes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-apps-gadgets-or-tools-cant-you-live-without&quot;&gt;What apps, gadgets or tools can’t you live without?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://slack.com&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; Reminders, my philosopher’s stone at work. With simple commands, I can remind myself or a colleague to do something. Need I say more? Since I have the app on my iPhone too, I can capture those work-related thoughts that spring up in the shower, at dinner or when I’m on holiday. It gets things out of my head, and only brings them back when needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I’ve been using &lt;a href=&quot;https://getpocket.com&quot;&gt;Pocket&lt;/a&gt; a fair amount to save blogs to read. Medium’s Reading List also comes in handy, but I’m trying to move away from the platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, too. It’s the app I use most. To both fill time productively and waste it. &lt;a href=&quot;https://mysocialsummary.com&quot;&gt;My Social Summary&lt;/a&gt; is great for catching up on Twitter without needing to scroll through Twitter. It looks for the most engaging tweets from lists you’ve built and sends you a daily digest. Definitely worth £3 a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve really taken to Post-it notes as a to-do list. I tried Trello but you’re not always able to add cards in meetings or ceremonies. Post-its are always at hand in GDS, so I can quickly capture sudden thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Here’s some &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@stevenjmesser/my-bootstrapped-stack-dca24da282cd&quot;&gt;stuff I’ve used at work&lt;/a&gt; before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-your-best-shortcut-or-life-hack&quot;&gt;What’s your best shortcut or life hack?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have to do something three times, automate it. If you can’t automate it, find a way to reduce the toil. You’ll immediately create more time to spend on things that really need it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;take-us-through-an-interesting-unusual-or-finicky-process-you-have-in-place-at-work&quot;&gt;Take us through an interesting, unusual, or finicky process you have in place at work&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you forget your work pass, you can’t get through many of the (mostly glass) doors. You end up staring forlornly at the people on the other side, who don’t know whether to let you in &lt;em&gt;sans&lt;/em&gt; ID. Sometimes several people walk past before you’re permitted to exit your dimension of uselessness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven’t worked out how to capitalise on this yet. It’s &lt;em&gt;a bit&lt;/em&gt; like a cigarette break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-do-you-keep-track-of-what-you-have-to-do&quot;&gt;How do you keep track of what you have to do?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like I said earlier, Slack Reminders and Post-it notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-your-favourite-side-project&quot;&gt;What’s your favourite side project?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m currently playing with &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; to refresh my &lt;a href=&quot;https://visitmy.website&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; and move blog posts away from Medium. But I’m also running out of kimchi so will have to make some more of that soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-are-you-currently-reading-or-what-do-you-recommend-to-read&quot;&gt;What are you currently reading, or what do you recommend to read?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m reading &lt;em&gt;Throwing Rocks at the Google Bus&lt;/em&gt; by Douglas Rushkoff for non-fiction, and &lt;em&gt;Memoirs of Hadrian&lt;/em&gt; by Marguerite Yourcenar for fiction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;who-else-would-you-like-to-see-answer-these-questions&quot;&gt;Who else would you like to see answer these questions?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MikeThacker&quot;&gt;Mike&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Ellayanor&quot;&gt;Ellie&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/pr0bablyfine&quot;&gt;Alex&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/johncutlefish&quot;&gt;John&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/emilylabram&quot;&gt;Emily&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/femkesvs&quot;&gt;Femke&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-the-best-advice-youve-ever-received&quot;&gt;What’s the best advice you’ve ever received?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘You can do whatever you want in life, as long as you don’t hurt anyone.’ Oh, and: ‘Work is just a way to pay the bills, but it helps if you enjoy it.’ Both from my dad.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://visitmy.website/2018/11/17/this-is-how-i-work-give-or-take/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://visitmy.website/2018/11/17/this-is-how-i-work-give-or-take/</guid>
        
        <category>Blogroll</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
