<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Steve Messer // Product manager</title>
    <description>Product person, GOV.UK, Government Digital Service. Web enthusiast, working in the open. Black Country boy living in London, UK.</description>
    <link>https://visitmy.website</link>
    <atom:link href="https://visitmy.website/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 19:38:58 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 19:38:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.6.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Gift</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Another sterling week working at pace on important problems. One of our senior product managers, Antonia, went on maternity leave this week and said she hoped I’d be around when she returned. I told her I probably would be: ‘Turning up to work is fun now, it’s not just a job.’ I am &lt;em&gt;incredibly&lt;/em&gt; lucky to be able to say that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;four-things-that-happened&quot;&gt;Four Things That Happened&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We did more things than this&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;one&quot;&gt;One&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We met our objective and finished the spin-up mission in 6 days. It’s a great achievement for everyone, especially pulling together in such a short space of time and, for much of the team, working on a new product. What was most impressive was how each person brought forward their own expertise, adding a unique and valuable facet to our research, testing and analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though we had three developers on the team, they covered hardware, computer science and creativity in code well. Our technical architect, Vitalie, was great in looking at the underlying, latent issues too, putting forward cards that prompted us to explore our support model. This was particularly great for me because I was about to ask him to do that, but he’d come about that slice of work through his own volition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was my first time working closely with a performance analyst too, which I really relished. Being able to ask product questions and getting evidence in return, evidence to support our endeavours, was fantastic. And my delivery manager, Nila, has been excellent in supporting the team and keeping things moving. She’s been so great that we’re going to see more of her next quarter. Woo!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Thursday we hooked up with my other team, Platform Health, to run through some load-testing. We were really pleased to see that the three short-term optimisations we’d made had had an effect, allowing us to serve 400 unique users per second for 20 consecutive minutes. There’s still more to be done to work out when it’ll fall over, but we’ve removed the most immediate risk – the rest is just long-term optimisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;two&quot;&gt;Two&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jen, Head of GOV.UK, raised a prescient point during one of our catch-ups. There’s been some trepidation in Government Digital Service about how the organisation will be treated in next year’s spending review, the worry being that we might have less budget to do more things. What we’ve been doing over the past few weeks, delivering beneficial work for the country at a considerable pace during an unprecedented period, has really impressed Cabinet Office (apparently) and Government as a whole to show them what we’re capable of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our work has upheld the GDS principles and elements of the Service Standard, which just goes to prove the way we work and that transformation hasn’t finished, we’ve just entered a second age. We can all be really proud of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;three&quot;&gt;Three&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the first time, I had to give a firm ‘No’ to someone senior at GDS. It was a simple case of solutionising, really, and so quite easy to shift and redirect towards the desired outcome, but it’s uncommon to need to do it. They had proposed that a retention period should be applied to blog posts and that we could remove them after &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; years. That goes completely against the point of blogging in government and reeks of newspeak: we don’t alter history to make it fit the narrative we want to tell. We’re open, honest and accountable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, it turned out they were just worried about GDPR compliance and ensuring that people could exercise their right to have personal data removed, which I found out after some digging. I explained the platform, how it works and why we have it, then showed how their different policies apply to different sections of the platform and blogging activity. They saw how to reach their outcome then, so we’re updating the privacy notice and internal HR policies. A good improvement!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;four&quot;&gt;Four&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friday was a busy day with two interviews: one at HMRC, one phone interview at GDS. Both went really well, and I got along with everyone in the HMRC interview. Their work in London is particularly interesting, using product management practices to help shape policy – avant-garde work in government, if you ask me! I’m hoping that GDS pull their finger out and arrange a face-to-face interview next week, should I be successful, rather than waiting until after Christmas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reflections&quot;&gt;Reflections&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-i-learned&quot;&gt;What I Learned&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continued to learn how to work with team members from diverse backgrounds and with different emotional needs. Looking forward to hearing comments from people in our remote retro, so I can learn more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-i-could-do-better&quot;&gt;What I Could Do Better&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to say without that retro, to be honest, we’ve been so immediately focussed on the work in front of us, there hasn’t been time to think about much else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reading&quot;&gt;Reading&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.ldodds.com/2016/11/10/donate-to-the-commons-this-holiday-season/&quot;&gt;Donate to the commons this holiday season&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.technologyreview.com/the-download/612518/250-pages-of-internal-facebook-files-were-just-dumped-online-here-are-the-6-key/&quot;&gt;250 pages of internal Facebook files were just dumped online – here are the 6 key takeaways&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cigionline.org/publications/four-internets-geopolitics-digital-governance&quot;&gt;Four Internets: The Geopolitics of Digital Governance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/12/10/obituaries/evelyn-berezin-dead.html&quot;&gt;Evelyn Berezin, 93, Dies; Built the First True Word Processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://qz.com/1407235/porn-sites-collect-more-user-data-than-netflix-or-hulu-this-is-what-they-do-with-it/&quot;&gt;Porn sites collect more user data than Netflix or Hulu. This is what they do with it.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://visitmy.website/2018/12/14/the-gift/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://visitmy.website/2018/12/14/the-gift/</guid>
        
        <category>Weeknotes</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Spin Up</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The most fun I’ve had at work in a week on record. We’re doing work which sings to the vision of GOV.UK, making information about government and services simple, clearer and faster. Can’t knock it really, though it’s a heck of a change of pace from lying on the beach last week!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;four-things-that-happened&quot;&gt;Four Things That Happened&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We did more things than this&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;one&quot;&gt;One&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had the honour of spinning up a brand new sub-team. If you don’t count the outsourced teams I’ve run and looking after Platform Health while Martin’s off, this is my first time leading a multidisciplinary team at GDS – and I’m loving it. Staying aware of emotional energy while also having open conversations about delivering value for users is hugely enjoyable, especially when you have a team of excellent people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a quick kick-off on Tuesday from our lead technical architect, Tim, who explained that our team would be looking after dynamic content performance, the fourth of Platform Health’s OKRs that I set with Martin at the start of the quarter. After taking them through the technical introduction to GOV.UK’s architecture, I disbanded the group and set up to meet the following day at 9 a.m.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We grouped at 10 a.m. on Wednesday and spent pretty much the entire day defining our mission: the objective, what success would look like, our ways of working, and a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Johari_window&quot;&gt;Johari Window&lt;/a&gt; to start building a roadmap. By 4 p.m. we had a team charter, a roadmap, a prioritised backlog and a set of cards to tackle the following day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;two&quot;&gt;Two&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aditya, one of our developers on the new sub-team, is profoundly deaf and working with him has been a real eye-opener. It hasn’t been that hard to bear his needs in mind, and I’m making sure to address him directly and speak clearly, but it does change the pace of conversation some times. It makes us more metered and considered, if anything, as more effort needs to go into how one conducts oneself. We’re also filling in a doc before and after daily ceremonies too, so that he can read through the morning’s stand-up or the afternoon’s playback if he’s working from home. That’s one element I really like, having a record of what I said to check against what I manage to achieve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aditya is very pleasant to work with too, a gracious person who’s always smiling. We’ve a very considerate working culture at GDS but anyone would be hard pushed to &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; change their working patterns for him! Top bloke.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;three&quot;&gt;Three&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tijmenbr&quot;&gt;Tijmen&lt;/a&gt;, our tech lead, had dived headlong into the new work with Jon, another developer on the team whom we’ve borrowed from the Observe team. Following a quick run-through of dynamic content applications on GOV.UK, they got started on looking into previous load-testing we’d done on Platform Health. They were able to quickly identify opportunities for optimisations, adding &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/alphagov/finder-frontend/pull/722&quot;&gt;HTTP caching&lt;/a&gt; and content caching where appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tests on that pull request show an improvement on one Finder being able to serve 16x more requests with zero errors. The change was deployed later on that day and Tijmen put together a Grafana dashboard, to show the effect across all Finders and search pages on average, which I’ve been watching throughout most of Friday. It has reduced the number of requests being served by finder-frontend by 17%, widening the bottleneck and shifting the load onto our internal caches and the content delivery network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All within two days. Working at this rate, in a fast cycle, and achieving these results is testament to our working practice. It’s moments like this when you realise just what we can achieve in a short space of time with determination, skill and good frameworks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;four&quot;&gt;Four&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve got an interview at HMRC on Friday – woo! No news of the GDS PM interviews yet, but we’ll see what becomes of those. They’ve been delayed for quite a while now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reflections&quot;&gt;Reflections&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-i-learned&quot;&gt;What I Learned&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That I’m capable of leading a team…for a few days, anyway. Here’s hoping the next two weeks go just as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-i-could-do-better&quot;&gt;What I Could Do Better&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would have been better if I’d foreseen needing to spend the entirety of Wednesday with the new sub-team, rather than thinking I could juggle that and Platform Health too. That was naïve of me, but there weren’t any ill effects on the team so perhaps it’s not such a huge deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reading&quot;&gt;Reading&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read through a boat-load of stuff on holiday, here’s a selection of the best bits. There’s a very particular theme, perhaps based on the fact I was reading Douglas Rushkoff’s &lt;em&gt;Throwing Rocks at the Google Bus&lt;/em&gt; at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://svpg.com/common-pm-problem-areas/&quot;&gt;Common PM Problem Areas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.co.uk/article/a-short-history-of-facebooks-mess-ups&quot;&gt;Here’s a list of all the times that Facebook proved you can’t trust it&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/xwjden/targeted-advertising-is-ruining-the-internet-and-breaking-the-world&quot;&gt;Targeted Advertising Is Ruining the Internet and Breaking the World&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/2016/02/what-do-you-really-mean-by-business-transformation&quot;&gt;What Do You Really Mean by Business “Transformation”?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://avc.com/2014/07/platform-monopolies/&quot;&gt;Platform Monopolies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.co.uk/article/google-france-silicon-valley&quot;&gt;France is ditching Google to reclaim its online independence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://visitmy.website/2018/12/07/the-spin-up/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://visitmy.website/2018/12/07/the-spin-up/</guid>
        
        <category>Weeknotes</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>This is how I work…give or take</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dasbarrett&quot;&gt;Dan&lt;/a&gt; wanted to see how I work, so here’s what I do, based on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jukesie&quot;&gt;Jukesie’s&lt;/a&gt; rip-off of the Lifehacker ‘How I Work’ series. Other public service folk have written about &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@jukesie/this-is-how-we-work-give-or-take-6c8964cac85f&quot;&gt;how they work&lt;/a&gt; too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;: London, UK.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Current gig&lt;/strong&gt;: Associate product manager, Government Digital Service.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Current mobile device&lt;/strong&gt;: Samsung J5 for work, iPhone 8 for percy.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Current computer&lt;/strong&gt;: MacBook Air 13” for work. Mac Mini at home. Some hobby Raspberry Pis and a PC too.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;One word that best describes how you work&lt;/strong&gt;: Metered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;first-of-all-tell-us-a-little-about-your-background-and-how-you-got-to-where-you-are-today&quot;&gt;First of all, tell us a little about your background and how you got to where you are today&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Liked books and computers growing up. Spent a huge portion of my teenage years in my bedroom, tinkering on the Web or with computers. But I also enjoyed writing stories. Aged 16, I decided to focus on my Literature studies instead of Information Technology. It seemed to have…more prestige.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did my A-levels, went to Bath Spa Uni to study Creative Writing. Bought a Mac to stop me playing video games. It worked, and I had a lot of fun. The course was excellent with great teachers – check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bathspa.ac.uk/schools/liberal-arts/interest-areas/creative-writing/creative-writing-publications/&quot;&gt;some of the authors who’ve also studied at Bath Spa&lt;/a&gt; – and I had my sights set on a career in publishing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Graduated. Spent the next year continuing cheffing, then quit to get some work experience and make the most of my degree. Spent two weeks as a managing editorial assistant at Vintage Publishing (part of Random House) and was asked back for another week. A few months later, there’s an open position as an editorial assistant and they ask me to apply. Incredibly, I get it and dive into the literary publishing world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do that for 9 months. Move on to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.penguin.co.uk/company/publishers/vintage/jonathan-cape.html&quot;&gt;Jonathan Cape&lt;/a&gt;, attend a Booker Prize ceremony in my first week. It’s quite glitzy, maybe too glitzy, especially for a working class boy from Wolverhampton. I get the chance to work with some of the most eminent, prolific literary authors in the world. They even let me commission &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.penguin.co.uk/books/109/1093783/finally-my-ambulance/9780099575870.html&quot;&gt;a book of short stories&lt;/a&gt;. But I feel massively out of my depth and haven’t been to Oxbridge, like most others at my level. Self-doubt sets in. Work is naught but toil. I grow tired of the sausage factory. I quit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so I have a breakdown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The clouds pass after 6 months and I get a job at NOW TV, which was just starting out. See Agile and software development in action. Turns out that’s quite glitzy too, except I didn’t know that at school. IT is kind of cool now. &lt;em&gt;Hmm, maybe I could do tech after all.&lt;/em&gt; After some time in Operations, they initiate a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/transfers-takeovers&quot;&gt;TUPE process&lt;/a&gt; for an entire department and I need to find other work. &lt;a href=&quot;http://porism.com&quot;&gt;Porism&lt;/a&gt; has an opening for someone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I focus on increasing engagement and use of &lt;a href=&quot;http://lginformplus.local.gov.uk&quot;&gt;LG Inform Plus&lt;/a&gt;, then get the chance to redesign and launch a new version of &lt;a href=&quot;https://ecasework.com&quot;&gt;eCasework&lt;/a&gt;. We spent a year on that before it went live. Take-up wasn’t good. I wrestled with marketing techniques, sales, developing some features and trying to talk to the few users we had. Wasn’t really sure what I was doing. It was…enjoyable, but also like banging my head against a brick wall. Repeatedly. Every day. Because I’m leading myself blind. (However, I also learn some cool stuff about open data, local government and generally learn tons from &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MikeThacker&quot;&gt;Mike&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explaining my anguish to a friend, he suggests that I’m kind of doing product management. I read a few blogs, try out the techniques, and they work. &lt;em&gt;Hmm, maybe I could do tech after all.&lt;/em&gt; Attending the product management course at General Assembly gives me new skills. We start to grow eCasework and its user base. We develop features that people love. But I’m a bit hungry for more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apply for a job working on GOV.UK. They offer it to me. I’m overjoyed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now I’m just really, really happy. I’m at home. I’m back in my bedroom, tinkering on the Web and with computers, on a piece of the national infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;take-us-through-a-recent-workday&quot;&gt;Take us through a recent workday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a T-shaped structure to my week which I try to stick to. Mornings are for product thinking, writing cards or catching up on important emails, except on Wednesdays when I’ll meet &lt;a href=&quot;undefined&quot;&gt;Alex&lt;/a&gt; for coffee. Then it’s a catch-up with Delivery Manager and Tech Lead, followed by stand-up with the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Tuesdays and Wednesdays, the rest of the day is either meetings, team ceremonies or community meet-ups with other product managers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mondays, Thursdays and Fridays are a bit lighter: product thinking, analysing data and trends, and chats with other specialists, often dappled with the odd meeting here and there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The details of what actually happens can be found in &lt;a href=&quot;https://weeknot.es/@stevenjmesser&quot;&gt;my weeknotes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-apps-gadgets-or-tools-cant-you-live-without&quot;&gt;What apps, gadgets or tools can’t you live without?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://slack.com&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; Reminders, my philosopher’s stone at work. With simple commands, I can remind myself or a colleague to do something. Need I say more? Since I have the app on my iPhone too, I can capture those work-related thoughts that spring up in the shower, at dinner or when I’m on holiday. It gets things out of my head, and only brings them back when needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I’ve been using &lt;a href=&quot;https://getpocket.com&quot;&gt;Pocket&lt;/a&gt; a fair amount to save blogs to read. Medium’s Reading List also comes in handy, but I’m trying to move away from the platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, too. It’s the app I use most. To both fill time productively and waste it. &lt;a href=&quot;https://mysocialsummary.com&quot;&gt;My Social Summary&lt;/a&gt; is great for catching up on Twitter without needing to scroll through Twitter. It looks for the most engaging tweets from lists you’ve built and sends you a daily digest. Definitely worth £3 a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve really taken to Post-it notes as a to-do list. I tried Trello but you’re not always able to add cards in meetings or ceremonies. Post-its are always at hand in GDS, so I can quickly capture sudden thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Here’s some &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@stevenjmesser/my-bootstrapped-stack-dca24da282cd&quot;&gt;stuff I’ve used at work&lt;/a&gt; before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-your-best-shortcut-or-life-hack&quot;&gt;What’s your best shortcut or life hack?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have to do something three times, automate it. If you can’t automate it, find a way to reduce the toil. You’ll immediately create more time to spend on things that really need it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;take-us-through-an-interesting-unusual-or-finicky-process-you-have-in-place-at-work&quot;&gt;Take us through an interesting, unusual, or finicky process you have in place at work&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you forget your work pass, you can’t get through many of the (mostly glass) doors. You end up staring forlornly at the people on the other side, who don’t know whether to let you in &lt;em&gt;sans&lt;/em&gt; ID. Sometimes several people walk past before you’re permitted to exit your dimension of uselessness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven’t worked out how to capitalise on this yet. It’s &lt;em&gt;a bit&lt;/em&gt; like a cigarette break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-do-you-keep-track-of-what-you-have-to-do&quot;&gt;How do you keep track of what you have to do?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like I said earlier, Slack Reminders and Post-it notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-your-favourite-side-project&quot;&gt;What’s your favourite side project?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m currently playing with &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; to refresh my &lt;a href=&quot;https://visitmy.website&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; and move blog posts away from Medium. But I’m also running out of kimchi so will have to make some more of that soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-are-you-currently-reading-or-what-do-you-recommend-to-read&quot;&gt;What are you currently reading, or what do you recommend to read?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m reading &lt;em&gt;Throwing Rocks at the Google Bus&lt;/em&gt; by Douglas Rushkoff for non-fiction, and &lt;em&gt;Memoirs of Hadrian&lt;/em&gt; by Marguerite Yourcenar for fiction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;who-else-would-you-like-to-see-answer-these-questions&quot;&gt;Who else would you like to see answer these questions?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MikeThacker&quot;&gt;Mike&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Ellayanor&quot;&gt;Ellie&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/pr0bablyfine&quot;&gt;Alex&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/johncutlefish&quot;&gt;John&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/emilylabram&quot;&gt;Emily&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/femkesvs&quot;&gt;Femke&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-the-best-advice-youve-ever-received&quot;&gt;What’s the best advice you’ve ever received?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘You can do whatever you want in life, as long as you don’t hurt anyone.’ Oh, and: ‘Work is just a way to pay the bills, but it helps if you enjoy it.’ Both from my dad.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://visitmy.website/2018/11/17/this-is-how-i-work-give-or-take/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://visitmy.website/2018/11/17/this-is-how-i-work-give-or-take/</guid>
        
        <category>How I Work</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Wind Down</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A four-day week spent closing open loops. Took yesterday off to pack for my holiday which I’m really, &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; looking forward to – especially because it’s supposed to drop to 1°C next week!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;four-things-that-happened&quot;&gt;Four Things That Happened&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We did more things than this&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;one&quot;&gt;One&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;undefined&quot;&gt;John Cutler&lt;/a&gt; spared us an hour to chat product, and it was really beneficial. We talked quite a bit about valuing non-feature work, how it’s important and continuous improvement needs to happen under the hood too. That sort of work is our main focus on Platform Health, really, and selling it to ‘the business’ isn’t too hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But how this work is described by senior teams can irk me. Platform work is often referred to as ‘keeping the lights on’, but it’s really much more than that: it’s chopping wood, filling buckets, building aqueducts…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John mentioned Cost of Delay and it’s a useful prism to view all platform work through. &lt;em&gt;Does the value opened up by doing this story diminish over time?&lt;/em&gt; That sort of thinking allows you to take on anything urgent and create value in the short term while also keeping an eye on the long term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;two&quot;&gt;Two&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Had check-in with the programme team on Wednesday, or at least we were supposed to have check-in with them. The majority of them weren’t there, which was a let down as we had some important things to tell them. Really frustrating when you’ve had to work through lunch to get the presentation together too, because there’s so little time on Tuesdays and Wednesdays what with all the meetings. And putting the slides together on Monday would miss 20 per cent out of the last two weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite that, our new Head of Product, Leanne, was there in force and tried her best to accommodate us. She was pleased with our progress and some of the optimisations we’ve brought to the publishing pipeline, wanting to push us to show it off. I’m really keen to get the team showing off what they’ve done because, as I always say, it’s not sexy work but it’s damn-near as important as building features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;three&quot;&gt;Three&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The excellent &lt;a href=&quot;undefined&quot;&gt;Emily&lt;/a&gt; gave our team a run-down of SLIs, SLOs and SLAs – henceforth known as SLXs – and how they can create psychological safety in our work. We’ve had a go at creating one already (which I covered in &lt;a href=&quot;https://weeknot.es/the-delivery-93a08085cc32&quot;&gt;S02E03&lt;/a&gt;) and this was included in her slides, which meant to work was framed much better than I had introduced it to them. As Emily spoke about the noise of alerting and how to make alerts more meaningful, there was lots of nodding amongst the group. It certainly hit home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re going to be looking at building SLOs for the other jobs of GOV.UK soon, once some important Brexity business is out of the way. In lieu of an actual stress-test of the pipeline, making our current data more meaningful will provide a decent, actionable contingency for the months ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;four&quot;&gt;Four&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Darren Barnes from ONS came to talk about and demonstrate the amazing &lt;a href=&quot;https://gss.civilservice.gov.uk/guidance/the-gss-data-project/&quot;&gt;GSS Data&lt;/a&gt; project. Using linked data principles and technologies such as concept schemes, triple stores, URIs and all that other stuff, they’ve pulled together a neat open data portal that allows you to find statistics about stuff. It was super impressive, and it was nice to hear that they held &lt;a href=&quot;undefined&quot;&gt;Mike&lt;/a&gt;’s work on &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.esd.org.uk/about&quot;&gt;ESD and LG Inform&lt;/a&gt; in high regard – as an exemplar of what could be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reflections&quot;&gt;Reflections&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-i-learned&quot;&gt;What I Learned&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That everything I learned about linked data at Porism could be useful during my time at GDS. That was quite a surprise. Darren was throwing out technical terms left, right and centre – and I understood everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-i-could-do-better&quot;&gt;What I Could Do Better&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compose myself during meetings. I get very excited about things and that’s not always good, especially if your body language communicates a commitment to a project prematurely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reading&quot;&gt;Reading&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hackernoon.com/prioritizing-non-feature-work-and-continuous-improvement-bad2a612d860&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prioritizing “Non-Feature” Work and Continuous Improvement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thoughtworks.com/radar&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Emerging Tech Trends for 2018&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/analyzing-experiment-outcomes/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Analyzing Experiment Outcomes: Beyond Average Treatment Effect&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.niemanlab.org/2018/11/how-the-wall-street-journal-is-preparing-its-journalists-to-detect-deepfakes/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How The Wall Street Journal is preparing its journalists to detect deepfakes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://visitmy.website/2018/11/17/the-wind-down/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://visitmy.website/2018/11/17/the-wind-down/</guid>
        
        <category>Weeknotes</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Staying of the Course</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We’re reaching the mid-point of the quarter, so there’s a flurry of things going on. The team is chugging through work at a good pace, but there’s still so much to do if we’re to achieve the objective for our mission. Opening up conversation on how we’ll meet those goals has been good, but we’re subject to so many external factors it can sometimes be tough to stay the course. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@stevenjmesser/dealing-with-domineering-clients-67052f02f551&quot;&gt;Sailing analogies&lt;/a&gt; are quite good for framing team-work and missions, I find.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;five-things-that-happened&quot;&gt;Five Things That Happened&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We did more things than this&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;one&quot;&gt;One&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having migrated the first two applications over to a new hosting provider, we had a v-team retrospective with our friends in Reliability Engineering. It worked well, acting as a review of the steps we’d previously taken, giving us the chance to improve the run book for next time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was one gotcha to eliminate for next time: making sure that the release pipeline is clear and no one’s forgotten to release Puppet changes specifically. Our lead architect, Tim, reminded everyone that it was their responsibility to own a pull request (and associated changes) all the way through and to keep the deployment pipeline as clear as possible. &lt;a href=&quot;https://gds-way.cloudapps.digital/standards/continuous-delivery.html#use-continuous-delivery&quot;&gt;Continuous delivery&lt;/a&gt; relies on principles rather than process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;two&quot;&gt;Two&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Had our first GOV.UK product manager fortnightly meet-up with the new Head of Product, Leanne. It was a bit full-on for her first session, but then again it was probably a perfect introduction for someone who’s going to own our high-level strategy for the forseeable future. We touched briefly on the product triage process – which has dominated most fortnightly meetings in recent months – and it was relatively trivial as opposed to the usual furore. That was good to see. Chatter about it had been dividing us as a community of late, but we were unified on it this week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rob used the &lt;a href=&quot;http://leancoffee.org&quot;&gt;Lean Coffee&lt;/a&gt; approach to decide what we’d talk about next. Everyone wanted to talk overwhelmingly about the roadmap and the next 12 months – which, unfortunately, we’re not able to &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.productplan.com/p/bUmH4fHC0hOivX-E2LYMu2hg9uEhkWp_&quot;&gt;make public like in previous years&lt;/a&gt;. I’m not entirely certain on the reasons behind that but I don’t think it was an internal decision, because &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/service-manual/agile-delivery/developing-a-roadmap&quot;&gt;using roadmaps as an open communication tool is a principle we hold dear&lt;/a&gt;. I suspect it could be more to do with our roadmap being seen as a delivery plan rather than &lt;a href=&quot;https://svpg.com/vision-vs-strategy/&quot;&gt;a strategy to achieving a multipart vision&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my view, GOV.UK has pretty much (but not totally) achieved its &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.stanford.edu/class/ee204/ProductMarketFit.html&quot;&gt;product–market fit&lt;/a&gt; and should now be concerned with scaling. The issue we have is that new and existing departments on GOV.UK often bring solutionised features to us as problems, and many expect their requests to be built out. We have a good set of products and features to offer to government but I’m not sure where the sales process happens, and we need an amount of feedback from those interactions to influence our product iterations. In the meantime there’s plenty of work to be done on scaling the platform’s architecture and that’s something we can do with application- and machine-level data alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;three&quot;&gt;Three&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though it meant I missed a team lunch for a new starter on Platform Health, we took one and half hours out of a busy day to map the problem space of publishing, and it was really beneficial. Myself, Humin, Sam and Mark, all product managers on publishing aspects of the platform, wrote up the high level problems we see with scaling GOV.UK and grouped those by theme. It’s intended to form a strategy for solving those problems, but in a time when reliability is perhaps more important than efficiency, I’m not sure how much of it we’ll be able to work on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That aside, it was excellent to get together with PMs from across the programme and join up our thinking. I’ve been meaning to do that ever since joining Platform Health, bringing other product teams and their goals into our team’s thinking. Because, arguably, I am currently a &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/productschool/what-is-technical-product-management-anyway-d36deb3216d0&quot;&gt;technical product manager&lt;/a&gt; whether I intended to become one or not. And technical product management has internal teams as its users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’ve got a couple of product ideas bobbing around and have a hankering to scratch the ‘build a thing’ itch, so if you want to get involved in a side hustle, &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:stevenjmesser@gmail.com&quot;&gt;hit me up&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;four&quot;&gt;Four&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spent two hours coming up with options to upgrade and manage our Elasticsearch with Bevan. If I’m honest, I wasn’t really sure how to approach this, but I knew we needed a range of options plus their technical, financial and product-focussed impacts to present to the programme team for them to choose from. Sort of like a Choose Your Own Adventure business case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/5772/1*49VaAAfIY-cEY5d6THUG8Q.png&quot; alt=&quot;A matrix of options plotted against risks, benefits, technical complexity, delivery time and financial costs&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;A matrix of options plotted against risks, benefits, technical complexity, delivery time and financial costs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I freestyled a matrix of Post-it notes, detailing the different stages and options plotted against the risks, benefits, technical complexity, delivery time and financial costs of each. It actually worked quite well and we got all the brainstorming done inside of the meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a point was raised, there would usually be a counterpoint to consider for a different option, meaning we grew a body of thoughts quite quickly. Much better than scrolling up and down a document, scribbling in part-thoughts and half-formed sentences, which I’ve done previously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;five&quot;&gt;Five&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bevan covered how we code and quality assure products and features at GOV.UK. This was off the back of our retrospective, where Alan had asked to be introduced to our process and I was keen to hear about it too. We’d been told about it informally but found this proper session really useful. And it was good to understand the inner workings as compared to the development process at previous places I’ve worked. It’s pretty fast at GOV.UK and everything’s to such a high quality, I was just really intrigued to know more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It hangs off a set of principles rather than defined processes. I’m paraphrasing here, but essentially our developers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;are responsible for their code and features throughout the development and release lifecycle,&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;should test their code and its dependencies,&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;have code peer-reviewed for quality,&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;should QA their code in integration, either individually or with product managers, and&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;use continuous delivery to release small, frequent changes.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s more in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://gds-way.cloudapps.digital&quot;&gt;GDS Way&lt;/a&gt; but bear in mind that this works for us and may not suit other teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reflections&quot;&gt;Reflections&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-i-learned&quot;&gt;What I Learned&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That all these facilitation techniques and Post-it noting practices are just methods for getting ideas out. Yes, I was skeptical at first and I know many people still are, but they work. If you’re struggling to have productive conversations at work and meetings go round in circles, try something different. There’s shitloads of blogs and other websites with loads of approaches you can try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-i-could-do-better&quot;&gt;What I Could Do Better&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ask people to give feedback to my line manager. A colleague came over and praised me for some work, saying they’d pass it on, but I’ve neglected to ask people to do that in the past. I’m going to make sure I know who line manages each person on our team, too, so I can furnish them with all the good work our people do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reading&quot;&gt;Reading&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/content/f8e9c2ea-b29b-11e8-87e0-d84e0d934341&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Governments fail to capitalise on swaths of open data&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://freedomhouse.org/report/freedom-net/freedom-net-2018/rise-digital-authoritarianism&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Freedom on the Net 2018: The Rise of Digital Authoritarianism&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mindtheproduct.com/2018/10/escape-from-the-feature-roadmap-to-outcome-driven-development/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Escape From the Feature Roadmap to Outcome-driven Development - Mind the Product&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://logicmag.io/05-how-to-kill-your-tech-industry/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How To Kill Your Tech Industry&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://visitmy.website/2018/11/10/the-staying-of-the-course/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://visitmy.website/2018/11/10/the-staying-of-the-course/</guid>
        
        <category>Weeknotes</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
