<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>NaBloPoMo – Steve Messer // Product manager</title>
    <description>Things I've written during National Blog Posting Month.</description>
    <link>https://visitmy.website</link>
    <atom:link href="https://visitmy.website/feed.nablopomo.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 09:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 09:00:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Going dark</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A few pieces I’ve written during NaBloPoMo 2020 have been fun to write. Others were more strained.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure any of them made a good point. I’d like to improve my writing, and committing to writing weeknotes means I can often lose my steam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, good writing starts with good reading, and my note-taking habits have changed recently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By reducing the amount of things I write and publish, I should hopefully give more space for thoughts to percolate, develop and crystallise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’m going dark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;There is a clear overproduction of things (intangible and tangible) that have been created uncritically, unquestioningly, without needing to meet any type of standard other than existing. New output is produced everyday due to the accessibility of tools for creation… We have grown accustomed to shutting off our critical thinking faculties… Critical thinking in action by consumers and creators leads to output being respected and valued accurately, which pushes culture forward towards the infinite cultural mindset.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;https://maekan.com/article/the-modern-creators-paradigm &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://visitmy.website/2020/11/16/going-dark/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://visitmy.website/2020/11/16/going-dark/</guid>
        
        <category>Blogroll</category>
        
        <category>NaBloPoMo</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Propaganda: leading teams with memes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Part 3 of 3&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/11/07/rhetoric/&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt; I looked at the echoes of Aristotle’s rhetorical triangle of appeal in the ‘Users, Trust, Delivery’ three-sided mantra. It told both the why and the how.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It tells both the why and the how. Short, memorable phrases like this are easy to recall in tense, high-risk moments, making it an effective communication. It not only makes sense, it works. And, truth be told, the phrase was good propaganda too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of the people employed at GDS in the early days were obsessed about Internet-era ways of working to reduce waste, giving each other psychological safety to excel creatively and focusing almost myopically on user needs. So those three words really resonated with them, appealing to their views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the workforce was organised and co-ordinated around those principles, they concentrated their efforts entirely on those guiding policies. In his book &lt;em&gt;Good Strategy/Bad Strategy&lt;/em&gt;, Richard Rumelt says how ‘good strategy and good organisation lie in specialising on the right activities and imposing only the essential amount of co-ordination.’ Hacking co-ordination with a meme is truly brilliant, so find out what gets people going. Come up with a phrase to rally around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;making-your-own-meme&quot;&gt;Making your own meme&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a go at making our own meme…though nothing quite as crafted as ‘Trust, Users, Delivery’. (Admittedly, this is a rather in-depth essay on &lt;em&gt;just one&lt;/em&gt; motto, of which GDS has many!) When a colleague uttered the words ‘Boring magic’ to describe what we do at GOV.UK, it struck a chord. A lot of people agreed with how it bundled up the value we provide in a humble way. We’re not looking to conquer the world with technology, we’re just hoping to make interacting with government digitally less tedious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I wrote a &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/01/08/boring-magic/&quot;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; and we made a &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/stevenjmesser/status/1226099069996732418&quot;&gt;sticker&lt;/a&gt;, to see if the idea would catch on. People shared the article. They asked for a sticker and put it on their laptops. The meme started to spread. And sometimes, when we’re in meetings, people use the phrase ‘boring magic’ as shorthand to refer to methods for making public services better. It’s on &lt;a href=&quot;https://apolitical.co/en/solution_article/what-is-digital-transformation&quot;&gt;digital government websites&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://noisydecentgraphics.typepad.com/design/2020/11/rdi-insights-talk-tuesday-night.html&quot;&gt;elsewhere&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tactic isn’t one we discovered, it has &lt;a href=&quot;https://gilest.org/2017/stickers/&quot;&gt;history&lt;/a&gt;. Propaganda works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-do-your-leaders-say-to-inspire-action-in-you&quot;&gt;What do your leaders say to inspire action in you?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These slogans are everywhere, but there must be more out there. I’d love to hear about other mantras, little morsels of communication, that have popped up in other organisations, so tell me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s your meme? What does it mean? How was it made? Why does it appeal? What situations has it got you through? And, most importantly, who rallies around it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;further-reading&quot;&gt;Further reading&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://londonpublishingpartnership.co.uk/digital-transformation-at-scale/&quot;&gt;Digital Transformation at Scale: Why the Strategy Is Delivery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://basecamp.com/guides/how-we-communicate&quot;&gt;The Basecamp Guide to Internal Communication&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.palgrave.com/gp/book/9781137465924&quot;&gt;Winning Minds: Secrets From the Language of Leadership&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://goodbadstrategy.com&quot;&gt;Good Strategy/Bad Strategy: The Difference and Why it Matters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://visitmy.website/2020/11/08/propaganda/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://visitmy.website/2020/11/08/propaganda/</guid>
        
        <category>Digital government</category>
        
        <category>NaBloPoMo</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rhetoric: leading teams with memes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Part 2 of 3&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/11/06/users-trust-delivery/&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt; I looked at how GDS’s original ‘Trust, Users, Delivery’ motto was used to communicate concisely the collective direction and culture of the organisation. The sum of the words were stronger than their individual messages, but in effect formed the constraints within which transformation could successfully happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taken together, the words make up the three elements of a formula for GDS’s digital transformation effort. If the focus is on meeting users’ needs, trusting our methods and delivering value, digital transformation can occur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what is it about the phrase that makes it so memorable and understandable?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It might be its echoes of Aristotle’s rhetorical triangle of appeal, which speechwriters use to make their writing really land with an audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pathos&quot;&gt;Pathos&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pathos is the appeal to people’s emotions. Writing deals with pathos when it has an emotional impact, and you can stir people’s emotions when you remind them that all their work is for the benefit of &lt;strong&gt;users&lt;/strong&gt;. Everyone cared (and still care) about making things better for users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;logos&quot;&gt;Logos&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Logos is the appeal to logic, presenting logical reasons to your case. At the time, agile methods and disruptive innovation were causing huge change in the tech sector. GDS set about to prove that you could apply the same techniques to transforming government. Hence, the strategy was &lt;strong&gt;delivery&lt;/strong&gt;. Everyone had used these methods before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ethos&quot;&gt;Ethos&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ethos is the appeal to authority and reputation of the speaker or writer, which can be transferred in tone. To present oneself as empathetic and understanding, speak about others and their needs – which inspires &lt;strong&gt;trust&lt;/strong&gt;. Everyone was aiming for the same goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, when it was uttered, the phrase would remind you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;we’re making change happen for the benefit of the country&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;we’re making change happen with methods we know will work, and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;we’re making change happen together.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It tells both the why and the how. Short, memorable phrases like this are easy to recall in tense, high-risk moments, making it an effective communication. It not only makes sense, it works too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next I’ll talk about how short memorable phrases make excellent propaganda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/11/08/propaganda/&quot;&gt;part 3&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://visitmy.website/2020/11/07/rhetoric/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://visitmy.website/2020/11/07/rhetoric/</guid>
        
        <category>Digital government</category>
        
        <category>NaBloPoMo</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Users, Trust, Delivery: leading teams with memes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Part 1 of 3&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Memes are a common concept to most people with an Internet connection these days. But before the multiplier effects of the Web, these morsels of communication were known as mottos, mantras, banners and phrases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I’ve been thinking about how these soundbites are used in leadership. I’m going to use an example from Government Digital Service (GDS) – where I work – as it’s one that’s closest to me. It’s rarely mentioned now but in the early days it was mantra to spur people on&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Trust, Users, Delivery.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It filled the gap between management and teams, where the necessity was to act autonomously, with very little opportunity for communication between the two group. People were busy! As I see it, the motto represented a way for management to address teams’ concerns as they went through great change, and a way for teams to express their pride in what they were creating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a meme – collective communication – to reduce the burden of having many, tailored, low-impact messages exchanged between teams and management. A phrase to rally around. It set the direction and the culture of the movement, with rumour and misinformation counteracted by collaboration and quality information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-motto&quot;&gt;The motto&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sum of these words were stronger than their individual messages, but in effect formed the constraints within which transformation could successfully happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;trust&quot;&gt;Trust&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trust was all about teams believing in management to make the right decisions, and management knowing that teams could be trusted to deliver. Trust was founded through shared principles such as ‘digital by default’, ‘putting users first’, ‘learning from the journey’, etc. (There’s more in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.slideshare.net/ColemanE/trust-users-delivery-gds-presentation-to-code-for-america-2012&quot;&gt;slide 4 of this presentation&lt;/a&gt;.) Because both factions knew the principles they were jointly working to, they didn’t need to settle people’s anxieties – which tend to arise during huge change projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;users&quot;&gt;Users&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Users pillar was dedicated to making &lt;a href=&quot;https://webarchive.nationalarchives.gov.uk/20120405091731/https://www.gov.uk/designprinciples#first&quot;&gt;users’ needs&lt;/a&gt; prominent in any discussion, design decision or product delivery. GDS was attempting to digitally transform government to make interacting with government simpler, clearer and faster for people. Like user personas, which remind digital teams who they’re creating things for, making users a part of the motto made them central to any considerations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;delivery&quot;&gt;Delivery&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Delivery aspect to the mantra captured the overall strategy. By using small, user-focused teams of developers, designers and managers to rebuild national infrastructure in an open way, they would prove that iterative, agile methods could transform government. The strategy was delivery, because results would prove the methods. In the face of adversity, faith in your methods comes as a comfort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/11/07/rhetoric/&quot;&gt;part 2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I wasn’t around in those days so these are my own assumptions having reverse-engineered the history and culture of GDS. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://visitmy.website/2020/11/06/users-trust-delivery/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://visitmy.website/2020/11/06/users-trust-delivery/</guid>
        
        <category>Digital government</category>
        
        <category>NaBloPoMo</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Many of the things people worry about are not really worth worrying about</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A few years ago I worked with film-maker Tomas Leach on a book for his documentary, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=J7arEQR8PdA&quot;&gt;In No Great Hurry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. The documentary is about the late Saul Leiter, a photographer who made the mundane magnificent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His style is unique. He takes pictures of boring things: condensation on a window, red umbrellas, taxi cars. Moments of urban life we’d all find commonplace. His composition made these scenes hard to unpick, a tad abstract. It would take a few moments to work out what you were seeing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was part of the allure. Shooting in the 1950s and 1960s, he was also an early pioneer of colour photography, which would equally draw the eye after a century of black and white photography.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saul’s photography was boring magic, without a doubt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His style causes us to slow down, to take in more of our surroundings. Inspect the ordinary for shades of delight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often I wonder whether we should be doing that more. In many aspects of life. We needn’t always be in motion, always moving on to the next thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if now is just enough?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’m a person who likes to postpone things. I see no reason for being in a rush. When you consider many of the things that people treat very seriously, you realise that they don’t deserve to be treated that seriously. And many of the things people worry about are not really worth worrying about. If I didn’t do anything more than my little book, would that have been enough? – Saul Leiter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Nothing came of the project, unfortunately. I experienced a severe bout of depression and couldn’t carry on. I really wish I had. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://visitmy.website/2020/11/05/many-things-people-worry-about-are-not-worth-worrying-about/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://visitmy.website/2020/11/05/many-things-people-worry-about-are-not-worth-worrying-about/</guid>
        
        <category>Blogroll</category>
        
        <category>NaBloPoMo</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Silly ideas</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the years I’ve kept these silly ideas for apps and gadgets in a note on my phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of them are really silly, bordering on pointless. For a while that was a particular focus, pointlessness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;An app for recording how quickly your toenails grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;An app that utilises AI to compute when your urine will start smelling of asparagus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;IoT-controlled wind chime, allowing you to turn it off when it’s annoying. It comes with a mini fan for when there’s no wind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there’s one I really want to build: Deliveroulette.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter your post code, a time to be fed and your budget, anything from £20 to £50. A bot will randomly select a restaurant, pick some things off the menu and place the order for you. A little while later the doorbell rings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A surprise dinner!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s better than TimeHop for toenails, anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://visitmy.website/2020/11/04/silly-ideas/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://visitmy.website/2020/11/04/silly-ideas/</guid>
        
        <category>Blogroll</category>
        
        <category>NaBloPoMo</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Google Search is the fast-food restaurant of knowledge</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Getting hold of knowledge is harder than we think. Most of what a search engine returns is information, and it’s our job to piece it together and generate knowledge: facts and things we know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google is really, really good at giving you information and lots of it. But, on average, how many of us click more than one link from the first five results? How many of us honestly take snippets from multiple sources and reason our own judgements?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In making it easy to get to information, Google has made itself a primary source of knowledge nutrition. But it is, at best, a fast-food restaurant: highly operationalised basic sustenance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it’s bad to rely on these behemoths. Most people don’t eat only at McDonald’s. So why feed our brains, our arguments, our faculties of reasoning, on a similar giant?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was product manager for GOV.UK’s site search engine, I set the team a project to learn more about how search engines work. For one week, they had to change their main search provider from Google to something else. Bing, Baidu, Dogpile, DuckDuckGo, Ecosia, or anything else. At the end of the week we talked about what was harder or took more effort, the features they missed from Google, and whether they wanted to carry on using that provider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people said yes, some people switched back to Google, but all of us learned how to find things in a different way. We had to actively engage our epistemological faculties and work with a corpus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then I’ve been using DuckDuckGo every day because I like the way it works. It reminds me of the early web, around 2002, a time when AltaVista and AskJeeves were big names in web search. Back then you’d fall into rabbit holes, starting on one page and diving through links, resurfacing to open up another, related rabbit hole by searching again. We built up information this way. You’d be delighted at what you found sometimes, learning something you hadn’t expected to find.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That pursuit of digging into a topic and building up your own knowledge base is losing ground to instant gratification. Voice assistants, in taking away the hassle of having to &lt;em&gt;read&lt;/em&gt;, could take it away all together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How might we make our own information-gathering Michelin starred? What skills do we need to refresh or relearn?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These habits of mind – how we weigh up information and find truth –  are helpful in many places. Not only in our work projects but also, most critically, at the ballot box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“We do not and cannot gain knowledge by passively recording reality in declarative sentences, as if we were baskets ready to be filled; instead, we must handle it interactively.” – Luciano Floridi&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Some things that inspired this post: Matt Webb’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://interconnected.org/home/2020/09/10/streak&quot;&gt;15 rules for blogging&lt;/a&gt;; Motherboard’s piece on popular culture as an information conduit and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en/article/y3gg3k/tiktok-influencer-isodope-is-stanning-for-nuclear-energy&quot;&gt;nuclear energy influencer Isodope&lt;/a&gt;; and The New Atlantis on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thenewatlantis.com/publications/hard-to-believe&quot;&gt;whether search engines make us gullible&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://visitmy.website/2020/11/03/google-fast-food-knowledge/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://visitmy.website/2020/11/03/google-fast-food-knowledge/</guid>
        
        <category>Blogroll</category>
        
        <category>NaBloPoMo</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The free-range future of work</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For organisations that use computers to get stuff done, the Internet means you can spread bits of your organisation out geographically and temporally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spreading a workforce geographically is usually called remote working or distributed working. That’s when workers aren’t necessarily close to the location of the main office, they live and work elsewhere. There’s also hybrid working, which is when people are expected to come into an office some times but can work from wherever they like the rest of the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spreading a workforce temporally is usually called flexible working or asynchronous working. That’s when workers aren’t always required to be working at the same time as each other. Although more often than not, there’s usually some ‘core hours’ workers have to be present and available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For various reasons, some groups of people have experimented with the opportunity the Internet has provided. It has allowed them to find new ways of doing things or new ways of living. And, for another variety of reasons, some people haven’t bothered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, in March, that all changed. Anyone who could work online, usually from a computer, was forced to try this stuff out. If their company hadn’t tried out these new ways of working, they became a guinea pig overnight. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cliffsnotes.com/literature/f/flowers-for-algernon/character-analysis/algernon&quot;&gt;mouse in a maze&lt;/a&gt;, without a scientist overseeing the experiment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That sucks because, as an organisation, you don’t know what works and what doesn’t. Your workers have been forced to try new things and will have reached their own conclusions. Some might like it, others might not be so keen. There will likely be some people for whom the experience has been traumatic, and those people are going to need our help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, ignoring whoever’s job it is to do this stuff, I think it’s time for people working on computers to look sideways (metaphorically) and help each other out. If you manage a team or you’re part of a team, it’s time to build your own New Normal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s some notes I’ve been making on free-range working&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. And you might like to read about &lt;a href=&quot;https://gds.blog.gov.uk/2020/10/07/what-happened-when-we-stopped-having-meetings-and-sending-emails/&quot;&gt;this experiment we tried with meetings and emails&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;notes-on-free-range-working&quot;&gt;Notes on free-range working&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We’re trying to create more serendipity for innovation, and make collaboration easier when we’re not in the same place. Show &amp;amp; Tells don’t have to be polished. Share progress, ideas and half-finished thoughts; invite people to comment on your work before it’s completed. This helps replicate putting work up on the wall and giving people a chance to comment on things, especially if they’re not on your team.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Check in on your colleagues’ home-working setup. Do they have space? Do they have a desk? Is it well-lit and comfortable? People with better working environments have a new kind of privilege, and so we should be equitable in our approach to free-range working.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When everyone you work with is on a screen, everyone is more equal – it’s harder for people to dominate the room. Also, we tend to stop talking over each other and let people finish what they were saying. Cultivate that atmosphere, creating the space for diverse or unheard voices to come to the fore.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Spontaneous socialising is a joy. Create a tea break channel and head in there when you’re going to make a cup of tea or coffee. Start a voice chat, either using your work laptop or some headphones connected to a phone.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;This term comes from Convivio, it’s all about having complete freedom of location, time, and responsibility. Steve Parks wrote &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.weareconvivio.com/free-range-working-an-introduction-27eb178db97c&quot;&gt;an introduction to free-range work&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://visitmy.website/2020/11/02/free-range-future-of-work/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://visitmy.website/2020/11/02/free-range-future-of-work/</guid>
        
        <category>Agile delivery</category>
        
        <category>NaBloPoMo</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why I write weeknotes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Each weekend I spend around 2 hours writing about what I did in the ~38 hours I spent at work that week. Why? Good question. Here’s a few reasons why spending more time than is necessary writing about work is a good thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;it-helps-me-think&quot;&gt;It helps me think&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing is a reflective practice. By going over what you did and writing about it, considering the objectives you were trying to meet and whether you got there, you actively think through and reflect on your work. You spot areas for improvement or things you forgot to do. Whereas otherwise you might canter through working life unsure of what worked or what didn’t, weeknoting makes you mindful of what you’re doing and why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;it-makes-professional-development-easier&quot;&gt;It makes professional development easier&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each month I chat with my line manager about what I’ve been doing at work and how I’m progressing against my professional objectives. Because those conversations are based around what I’ve been doing – and we do &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; – having it written down is super helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;it-builds-networks&quot;&gt;It builds networks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some times I’ve written about a problem we’ve been having, and other people have got in touch to say they have that problem too. Then we chat about it and think of a way forward, or they tell me how they’ve solved it before. This kind of networking, which happens outside your immediate work bubble, is spontaneous but just as useful as established, near networks at work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;it-builds-social-mobility&quot;&gt;It builds social mobility&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I come from a working class background and was the first person in my family to go to university. That means I didn’t learn about office culture, its politics and how to get ahead as a white-collar worker until I started working in an office. My dad is a builder, not a CEO or politician, so tales at the dinner table didn’t prepare me for where I work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I’ve found that by reading through other people’s weeknotes I can get a sense for how things are done. By writing my own notes and putting them out in the open, I have to actively walk the walk as much as talk the talk. By building credibility and showing my working in a sector renowned for cronyism, I’m hopefully proving my worth to prospective employers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;its-a-tiny-tiny-public-service&quot;&gt;It’s a tiny, tiny public service&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a way, the taxpayer is funding everything I do at work, so they probably have a right to know what I’m doing. And one day someone might fill my place and want to know what I got up to. Weeknotes are searchable records of (almost) everything I did at work, providing a history for those who come after me. &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/01/25/blogging-working-open/&quot;&gt;Blogging and working in the open&lt;/a&gt; as a public servant helps to open up government, form a dialogue with our audience, and share what we’ve learnt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the scale of public services they’re not &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; important, obviously. They’re not universal healthcare. But if one other person saves time solving a problem using my notes, that’s a good thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;further-reading&quot;&gt;Further reading&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://boingboing.net/2018/07/25/deep-nerd-ruminations.html&quot;&gt;Weeknotes: personal, public logs in the tradition of early blogging&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/job-garden/a-pre-history-of-weeknotes-plus-why-i-write-them-and-perhaps-why-you-should-too-week-16-31a4a5cbf7b0&quot;&gt;A pre-history of weeknotes, plus why I write them and perhaps why you should too&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://productforthepeople.xyz/the-why-of-weeknotes-c1cd98967842&quot;&gt;The why of weeknotes&lt;/a&gt; by Jukesie&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stamanfar.medium.com/the-why-of-weeknotes-cf4d7e8ad4e5&quot;&gt;The why of weeknotes&lt;/a&gt; by Sam Villis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gilest.org/2020/tips-for-writing-good-weeknotes/&quot;&gt;Tips for writing good weeknotes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://visitmy.website/2020/11/01/why-i-write-weeknotes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://visitmy.website/2020/11/01/why-i-write-weeknotes/</guid>
        
        <category>Blogroll</category>
        
        <category>NaBloPoMo</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>NaBloPoMo 2020</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;An index of things I have written during November 2020 for National Blog Posting Month. You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://visitmy.website/feed.nablopomo.xml&quot;&gt;follow my NaBloPoMo RSS feed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/11/01/why-i-write-weeknotes/&quot;&gt;Why I write weeknotes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/11/02/free-range-future-of-work/&quot;&gt;The free-range future of work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/11/03/google-fast-food-knowledge/&quot;&gt;Google Search is the fast-food restaurant of knowledge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/11/04/silly-ideas/&quot;&gt;Silly ideas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/11/05/many-things-people-worry-about-are-not-worth-worrying-about/&quot;&gt;Many of the things people worry about are not really worth worrying about&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/11/06/users-trust-delivery/&quot;&gt;Users, Trust, Delivery: leading teams with memes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/11/07/rhetoric/&quot;&gt;Rhetoric: leading teams with memes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/11/08/propaganda/&quot;&gt;Propaganda: leading teams with memes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020/11/16/going-dark/&quot;&gt;Going dark&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://visitmy.website/2020/11/01/nablopomo-2020/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://visitmy.website/2020/11/01/nablopomo-2020/</guid>
        
        <category>Blogroll</category>
        
        <category>NaBloPoMo</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
